What's up guys?
I'm sorry, I'm gonna... I'm gonna start playing.
I have many plans today.
I may click random.
I thought about it.
But let me just have a look at my characters real quick.
Look at that win streak!
Whoa!
I forgot we won!
Nice!
I'm so happy not to see a negative number on that left side.
We got Bethany unlocked.
No, we don't have Bethany.
Unlocked by beating hard mode with Lazarus without losing a life.
You know what?
Maybe it's time that we try that.
What else do I have?
Judas, we have this fucking guy.
This piece of shit right here.
Blue boy.
And we have Eve, the whore, Samson.
I'm actually kind of close to unlocking... I think I only need one more.
No, two.
Two characters and then I'm pretty much done with that.
Wait, did I miss one?
Oh, Jacob, three.
Three characters.
Wait, why are there two sets of question marks here and only one here?
Weird.
Also, that looks like a piece of cake.
Not meant in that way, but you know, literally it looks like a piece of cake.
A polyon or cheese.
Something like it.
I don't know why it looks like that.
Unlocked by beating... something.
I'm assuming... oh, maybe it's a boss I haven't met yet, you know?
Well, right now I have a lead.
We're gonna play as Lazarus because apparently we need to beat this in hard mode without... what was it?
Losing a life or something?
Yeah.
Without losing a life.
Let's work on that.
That sounds good to me.
I haven't played Lazarus in ten years.
And when I say ten years, I mean probably a couple weeks.
All right, let's go.
It's Isaac time, baby.
And it's always been Isaac.
Let me scan the room.
Okay, everything is clean.
No way!
We finally got the jump button!
That's insane.
He jumps in the direction he is currently moving.
Can be used to jump over gaps, enemies, and most obstacles.
It's not flying, but you know what?
I'm happy about this.
That's the first.
What a great start, huh?
Wait, it doesn't cost any mana?
Hold on a
Can I actually just keep jumping?
Infinitely?
That's crazy.
I gotta try it.
First, deal with these guys.
Nice.
Bombs and keys are key.
So wait, if I do... Oh my gosh!
Oh wait, I can't jump over... Yes, I can!
Dude!
Okay, that's massive.
Oh!
Yo!
Jumping is crazy.
Huge fan of it.
Sir?
Okay, it's time to release the beasts.
Okay, that's no problem.
Killing fast.
Good.
Okay guys, today we are going to be immune to any form of tilt.
There will be no tilt today.
There will be only smiles and handshakes and pancakes.
Man, I could eat a pancake, actually.
I'm still on my diet, though, so I shouldn't.
Today's going to be a great day, guys.
Because I know we're going to have good runs.
How do I know?
I just do.
I feel it in my bones!
Holy... Wait, what did I just explode it?
Why?
Oh, maybe he got hit by a random projectile from another enemy or something, and then... I don't know, actually.
No clue!
Weird.
So we cannot lose a life.
But if we do lose a life, it's okay.
We're just gonna keep playing, but we're gonna try not to lose a life.
Obviously easier said than done!
Okay, we're gonna juke them in here.
May not have been a good idea.
That's a great idea.
Man, being able to heal again.
Oh, I have a pill!
Wait, did I start with a pill?
I must have.
Also, I keep forgetting I can jump.
But I haven't had a need for it
The boss is here.
No tinted rocks, no jumping opportunities.
Damon's tail or demon.
80% of dropped hearts are replaced with keys.
All heart drops become black hearts.
Ha!
I mean, I can walk around with it until I get a bunch of keys and then drop it again.
I think that's going to be the strategy.
But obviously, I don't want to keep this on my person at all times, because I do need the hearts.
Three coins, that's not enough.
It is actually to buy that.
Then I get the three coins back.
That was, well, not worth it, I guess.
Ha!
I'm leaving.
Useless.
Oh lordy, this guy has a gravity thingy.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Okay, now we go down and left.
Okay, that wasn't too bad.
Teleport to the shop, okay.
Not too shabby.
Isn't this kind of a big first floor?
I feel like it's huge.
I guess I can use the hermit to get out of this room again, if I want to.
And again, all HP is kind of valuable to me right now, because I can't lose a life, right?
Nice.
Another key.
There's a tinted rock!
I'm gonna put it here in case we find a secret as well.
Watch.
Perfect placement.
Okay, well, that was good.
Those could have been hearts, actually, but because of the Damon's tail, they got converted to keys.
It's possible.
But we will never know.
I actually have a strong suspicion that we have a secret room right here.
Look at the footsteps on the floor leading to it!
100%.
Dude, is that actually an indicator?
Look at the footsteps!
Did I just discover the ultimate fucking clue?
Oh my god!
I need to pay attention to this!
Nice, more money.
Wait, I can jump over this.
Can I do it without taking damage, though?
Oh shit, I need to.
Gyapsie daisy!
Dude,
the job is crazy good!
Blow him up.
More money!
That's ten!
We can probably buy something in the shop now.
Man, what a first floor!
Doesn't get better than this.
We can get pills or... Let's save the money, actually.
The next shop we're gonna probably have enough to buy the expensive item.
That's the plan.
I like it.
I like plan.
That is good.
I guess I can use the jump as well to jump over creepin' shit.
You know?
It's kind of massive.
Oh, he has big flies.
I think this is a modified version of the Duke.
Is this Nuke?
Are we dealing with him again?
I'm not sure.
Getting a little dicey here.
Damn flies.
Wait, come
on.
Get some damage in.
Better.
Nice!
Run this way.
Play it ultra safe.
Let's see if we get a deal.
We don't.
Right rage.
Speed and range.
That's fantastic.
I mean, you can't be mad about that.
That is a great upgrade.
Dude, I have a feeling there's a secret here.
Look at the footsteps!
Oh wait, those are just bloodstains.
I knew it shouldn't have done that.
I just knew it wasn't there, you know?
I don't know why I said I thought it was there, because I didn't really.
I lied.
I really did.
I gaslit myself.
Burning basement?
Also 100% demon mode now.
Shit.
Come here.
Oi, oi, oi.
Don't you poop that at me.
Here's a bomb for you guys.
I couldn't deal with them anymore.
I'm sorry.
I had to kill them like that.
Wait, something else is alive in here.
Kidding.
They're all dead.
Oh god!
That was very close.
Mom's Pearl.
Increased chance of fighting soul hearts, black hearts, and bone hearts.
That's incredible.
And I wanted to replace this anyway.
I'm actually glad I just picked this up, because I kind of forgot I had that equipped.
It's huge.
We can jump and I see a stone.
Can I do it in a smart way though?
Just do it there.
I don't know if that had range to reach a potential secret room, but oh well.
Wait, I wonder if I can jump over enemies.
Dude, the jump range is kind of nuts as well.
Very nice.
I'll get blown up, son.
Oh, not the jittery guys.
These guys have had too much caffeine.
Speak enough.
I haven't had any today.
Dude, I'm gonna make a cup of coffee in like half an hour or something.
I need that, I need that caffeine in my, in my system.
It's the only way to stay on top of things when you're addicted to caffeine.
Which I think I may be.
I'm not sure.
Whoa, that was close.
Yeah.
Holy shit, the dodging skills are off the charts today.
Oh, okay.
That guy was fast.
That guy was mega fast.
We haven't had a treasure room.
You know what?
Let's go.
Fuck it.
I can jump over poop if I need to.
See ya, nerd.
Oh my goodness, come here.
I love the job.
The job is insane.
Okay, there's actually too much poop here.
There's too many jump over enemies.
It's confirmed.
Nice.
That's kind of huge.
Dude, this arena is kind of crazy.
Wait, we got to kill this guy now.
Come here.
Where you going, son?
This is not my finest moment here.
What I'm managing.
Good.
Why are you heading off to?
Okay, we got the underwear.
More range.
We're gonna have so much range.
We're not gonna jump in yet, of course.
Oh, wait.
Yeah, this way.
I go south.
Hey, it's actually pretty good just to get across the room as well.
Not even jumping over anything, just, you know.
Oh, wait, that's gonna be... Yeah, there we go.
That's a bomb for you guys.
Oh, I missed completely.
That is so sad.
Dude, when these guys get on fire, or like, mega fire, they start to run really fast.
Okay.
Actually, my range is really good right now.
10.75 range.
Isn't that kind of unheard of?
Like, this early in the game.
We definitely gotta abuse this.
Look at that range!
Wait, I'm hitting the jar half the time.
Okay, now what?
This way.
Oh!
Alright, that was an easy room.
Do I see tinted rocks?
I do not.
Hmm, I don't think I can destroy this flame.
Nah.
Yeah, he's mad now.
He's mad.
We got these guys.
They produce creep.
And look at this!
I can get to the pills!
Oh, that's not good.
I mean, I'm glad I used it now.
One makes you... No, not that one.
Okay, let's bomb this.
I'm gonna bomb it here, so that I can maybe find a secret.
Alright.
Not too shabby.
We got 14 coins!
Yeah, let's go in there.
We can probably get another coin here.
Come on, come on, damn.
Wait, the battery allows active items to store up to two charges?
Man, these items are shit for me.
I guess I'm gonna buy this.
Yeah, I was hoping for like a really nice item for 15 coins, you know?
Oh god, oh god, get it!
Skorpit!
Rant's Poison Cheers.
Oh, I guess that's good.
Not like amazing, but it's good, you know?
Uh, we do have the hermit, so we can utilize this here.
Yeah, why not?
Um, I'm gonna blow it up.
There's a chance we get blue hearts.
Damn.
Love it.
Hate it.
Okay, okay.
Take me out.
And now it's time to leave.
I think it's going pretty well.
3.5 damage.
Would love to get a little more damage, of course, but we have the poison, that's gonna help.
We have jump and a good amount of range.
So what I need now is a lot of big rooms with a lot of space.
That's the ideal way.
That was that last coin I could have needed if I had 14 coins, and I wanted the last one.
Okay, this is open, so obviously we go for it.
Uh, the moon?
Uh, I forgot what that was.
How good is this poison though?
Ooh, okay.
Let me see, I hit him once.
Let's see how long it takes.
Okay, he didn't die from that.
Dude, okay, he's hit twice?
Alright, two hits from that.
Oh man, I wish I had what do you call this spider mod.
So I can see the damage I'm doing here.
He's so valuable.
Bad trip?
Probably not a good idea.
Oh god, Jesus.
Somehow I didn't get hit, that's actually insane.
I thought for sure I would lose a lot of HP in here.
Give me that.
These guys though are dangerous.
Alrighty, now bad trip turns into a full health pill when at one health or less.
So it's actually a heal.
I need to come back here when I am low.
Wait, what is the moon?
The secret room!
Yes, go for it.
The moon is good.
Moon Joy is what I'm experiencing right now.
Why not?
Oh, uh, aha!
So far we haven't wasted a life.
This is good, good progress.
The poison is helping more than I think.
Book of Shadows, gain a damage nullifying shield.
Man, now I really wish I had that.
Oh wait, no, no.
I was thinking if I had bought the item from the shop, I could have two actives, but that's not what I did.
It gave me two charges on one active.
But I will pick it up just to get two out of books or two on the nerd thingy.
Yeah, now this one we can move, right?
Yeah, I'm gonna move it up here.
Ish.
I think that's where the secret room is.
There you go.
Okay, never mind.
Being able to jump is amazing.
Oi!
I can't believe that.
12 coins.
Uh, ooh, magic fingers.
Consumes one coin to damage all enemies in the room.
Ah, I want pills, I think.
I think that's the second puberty we've had.
Or was it pheromones we got earlier?
It's something with P.
We gotta find some kind of damage.
This is on the high priority list right now.
What's up, dude?
I mean, the poison does help a lot, actually, with the damage.
Why not?
Let's go.
No, no, no, actually.
Let's clear some rooms.
Maybe we hit one heart and then we can, then we can use the bad trip, right?
And heal up.
Very smart.
Oh, I thought they were gonna run into the fire.
Boink!
Haha!
Hey, come here!
Hey, hey!
The jumping is actually kind of sick.
I'm very calm.
Very clean so far.
I'm just gonna chill a little bit.
There we go.
The chariot.
Become invincible.
That one is actually not bad.
Go!
Meow, meow, meow.
Nice.
Oh!
I used it!
Did you see that?
The chariot was used so geniously.
It was a last-minute consideration I had there.
Okay, heal up.
Strength, plus one health.
Speed, damage, range, damn.
Just for the current room, though.
Splants a... Oh!
Actually, hold on now.
We can do this.
Watch.
Now we take this.
Ah, wait, should I have... should I waste the card here?
Just for this.
Could be worth it.
I'm gonna do it.
One more.
Come on, give me something good.
Okay, now we leave.
And then we heal up with the bad trip.
Insane gameplay.
Yo!
Come on now.
Maybe the optimal play would have been to destroy the blood donation machine before I left the room, but other than that, pretty good.
Pretty damn good.
Optimizing the money gains.
You're gonna keep shooting you bastard.
Oh!
Rude.
Oh my god.
Rocks are not suspicious at all.
Oh, shit.
Fuck!
Dude, I actually love the poison.
Hi, hello, hello.
Haha!
Popsidasey.
They even stay poisoned when they go down.
That's amazing.
It doesn't get better than this, ladies and gentlemen.
This is the run.
Destroy that.
Wait, we gained demon mode.
10% for that.
Why?
I guess whoever that was, was affiliated with the angel, I guess.
I'm assuming these two powers are at war, you know?
It's a constant, what do you call it, battle between good and evil.
Somehow.
Alright, here we go.
It's girdy.
I'm gonna fuck you up with my poison.
Oh, okay.
Good one, sir.
Oh, no.
I'm getting my ass kicked.
How come he's not getting poisoned?
Okay, there we go.
Oh, yai yai yai yai.
I'm dying, I'm dying.
He's gonna kill me.
Oh, my God.
Yes, I needed to do that.
I needed to.
Range and tears.
Oh, my God.
We are so low HP.
Do we have any healing?
Maybe the shop had something.
Let's go back to the shop.
I can't believe I've done this.
That was rough.
Oh, there's nothing here.
I may have to take this card.
Maybe it'll heal me.
I'm using it now.
I can't risk dying.
Can't risk dying.
Okay, now we're moving on.
These are the kind of plays you only get to see here.
That's right.
Okay, um, let's go up here.
What is that gray stuff on the floor?
Look at that.
We may have to dig there.
Ha ha.
Something about the poison I've noticed.
Regular enemies are always getting poisoned.
Bosses, there's only a chance to apply poison.
Wait a minute, if I had waited long enough for these guys to poop, like a lot of poop, maybe I could have, you know, indirectly farmed money that way.
You think about it.
Wait, I can hit these while they're down?
Ah, it's because they're red.
That's why.
It's not because of the poison.
Lovely.
Amazing.
I don't like these types of rooms, because I'm gonna be traversing them a lot, and I'm gonna randomly take damage, I think.
Okay, so there's two of these?
What the?
Isn't that unusual?
I'm coming back with more money.
Oh no.
Now it's your turn.
Lovely.
Actually, I shouldn't have taken that.
I wasted half a heart.
This takes a coin to get in, but I could use my bombs to potentially get more money.
I have minus one luck.
I'm not gonna be gambling here, so we're just gonna destroy things.
We actually do have a full heart in one room, so we can donate a little bit.
And now we destroy that.
Not bad.
Uh, I could donate again, then.
And destroy it.
Very nice.
Uh, I could donate to you as well, I guess, because I'm gonna use 15 in here.
Which one do I want?
Let's see, left or right?
Uh, Ili Billim, I have a tip.
Let's just go for that one.
Coupon?
What is that?
Makes one item in the shop or devil room free?
Oh, I should like that at random.
Holding this item passively guarantees that one item in the shop will be on sale for half price.
Dude!
Uh, well, I'm gonna be taking...
Here's the thing.
Ooh, here's the thing.
I kind of want to keep the jump, though.
We're gonna see if we get a devil room.
And if we do, what I mean is, I'm gonna have this equipped for the boss, and if we get a devil room, I'm gonna use it and then switch it out with jump again.
That's the plan.
Give me this.
Okay, yep.
Or I use it now and charge it up for the boss room.
It could be this one we get, right?
Damn!
Oh, well.
It was a gamble.
It didn't pay off.
The Bomberman is here.
I was just about to jump, but I can't, because I didn't have it equipped right now.
Oh, I'm in a corner.
I'm in a corner.
Actually, yeah, destroy some walls for me.
Mr. Boom.
Reusable bomb body?
Oh my god.
Why so many actives, though?
I don't need more actives.
Okay, let's put one here.
Damn.
Nothing.
We gotta keep charging this up.
Hopefully, we still have a lot of rooms left.
How did I miss?
Wait, why is everything question marks?
Am I, like, cursed with a question mark or something?
Remote detonator.
Oh my god, another active!
No.
Fuck off with that.
Too many actives.
Oi, oi, oi.
Come
on, nice.
Now we go here.
Oh, shit.
Oh, actually sick.
Hit poison, nerds.
Oi, oi, oi.
Oi.
This guy's already poisoned.
Battery.
Okay, that's interesting.
Um, can I walk through that door without picking that battery up, though?
That's the question.
Yes, I can.
Nice.
Oh, no.
Dude, really?
Oi.
Man, this room was crazy.
Run!
What the...
Man, they're speeding up.
Uh, secondhand increases the duration of status effects.
Um, nah.
It's not intriguing.
Man, this is a big-ass place.
I need the boss now, because I got the thing ready.
I'm ready to get a free devil deal, come on.
Or I go back to the shop and get a free one there, I could do that.
Knowing my luck right now, though, it's probably gonna make the key free, right?
Okay, the boss is in here, I guess.
Man, they're so annoying.
Yeah, two shots is enough to kill him.
Nice.
Now, where are the tinted rocks at?
More importantly, where's the boss?
Nice and slow.
No reason to be, uh, an action hero here.
Ah.
That's unfortunate.
Nice.
There's the boss!
Uh, we're going for it.
Maybe I should grab half a heart before I go in.
This is very pit-dancing right now, but I gotta do it.
The last boss I fought, I survived with half an HP, right?
Can't be too safe.
Not that one, there's a half a heart up here.
There it is.
Oh, wait a minute, I never took this?
Oh, right, that was that thing.
Right.
Weird that it was a question mark when I entered.
Shouldn't that have been revealed as Mr. Boom?
Isn't that a bit... is that a bug?
That feels like a bug to me.
Uh, the shop, there's nothing in the shop I want.
Okay, time to... actually, I could go in here, since I have hearts to spare.
Not a bad idea.
Except nothing was in here.
Very sad.
Try and blow some holes.
Ha, ha, ha.
Well, well, well.
Yeah, I take it.
The Empress, damage speed, wonderful.
Can't be mad about that.
Oh, wait a minute, I have a way out here, then.
Yep, no need to take damage.
All right, we got 36% chance of a devil man appearing.
I hope he appears, so we can have a chance to get an item for free.
That would be sick.
It's Vistula.
I can jump to that little island down there if I want to.
Okay, now they split up.
Yep, yep, yep.
No!
Fuck my muscle memory, dude!
Well, there it is.
I hope I don't get a devil man now.
Please no devil man.
I poisoned my own mind, by the way, when I said I can jump to that island there.
Okay, we didn't get a devil room anyway, so everything's fine.
Shot speed up, and what else?
Increases chance of planetariums?
What is it?
I mean, I know what a planetarium is, but I don't know what it is.
You know what I mean?
What is the random card?
The world!
You know what?
I'm actually gonna use it.
Um, wait.
Let me see that again.
For the current room.
Damage speed.
I will keep the world.
Yeah, and move on.
Yep, that's the plan.
Let's go.
Get in here.
Glass eye!
Ooh!
Oh, that's a crazy room!
I hate these little gray flies.
What a sniper shot, though, just now.
Did you see that?
Where it just took that guy out?
That was beautiful.
Run fast!
Drive by!
Not bad.
Wait, what?
What's happening here?
Oh, there we go.
Dude, my strategy's kind of working.
Oh, no, not this.
Yeah, we gotta take them one at a time.
Play it safe.
Okay.
Very good!
Wow, I dealt with that pretty nicely.
I expected to take a lot of damage.
Okay, good to know that guy has lasers.
Oi, oi, oi, oi, oi.
You want hearts?
Hmm, maybe.
I'll come back.
Oi, oi, that was actually close.
Hey, I poisoned his little buddy!
I wonder if that damages him as well.
Wait, we're gonna get three out of three on book now!
I've never seen this before!
Satanic Bible!
Yeah, and we just gained, uh, what was it called?
A bookworm?
Let's see here.
Activating this before defeating the current floor's boss will replace the boss reward with a devil deal item that costs health to claim!
Ha!
Okay.
So, I'm just gonna do that now.
Yes!
Satanism!
And, uh, the coupon.
And monster manual.
I guess I can also summon that.
Yes, you're with me now.
Now we take this again.
So, what ex...
Oh!
Right, that's what bookworm does.
Because we get glasses, I guess.
We shoot, uh...
We see double, or whatever, you know?
I don't know what the logic is there, but something like that.
Oh, I thought that was an enemy, huh?
Launch...
Yeah, that's nice.
Beautiful stuff.
And now we use this!
The world has been revealed.
I see the treasure room.
We're definitely gonna...
Oh, actually, I want to go to the shop so I can use this coupon ASAP.
What even are these enemies?
That's a new one.
Oh my god, oh my god!
Good.
Is my body actually helping me at all?
Yeah, it's dealing a little damage.
Oh my god.
Good, good, good, good.
Where are you appearing?
There you are.
What a shot, what a shot!
Okay.
I do kind of regret a little bit leaving the jump behind, but then again, I don't.
The coupon is kind of crazy.
Okay, let's go to the shop first.
I see the secret room as well, but shop first.
Is that worth it?
Maybe not yet.
Oh man, how did you hit me?
Okay!
Shop time!
Now, what I can do here is actually, I can buy this first.
So, to increase my chances of...
Oh, guys, shooting at me.
Okay, I'm gonna buy...
Let's see.
We're gonna, we're gonna buy this.
Why is it that one?
Fuck me.
And then we're gonna buy this.
Yeah!
Buddy in a box grants a following familiar with a randomized appearance, fire rate, damage, and bonus tier effects.
The familiar traits are randomized at the start of each new floor.
Alrighty, that's good.
We have a little...
a very grown man looking baby.
Look at those eyebrows.
Kinda scary.
Donate the rest.
Do I want to carry this around?
A ventricle razor?
Not really.
Okay, let's see here.
Secret room time.
What is that?
That's a new one.
And extra...
Oh!
Oh no!
But that's useless for me!
Because I need to not lose any lives, right?
That's the whole point of this.
Hahaha!
Oh well.
If we transition into a normal run, I guess it'll be useful.
Oh my gosh.
Destroy all the rocks!
Yeah!
Open up the path for me.
I like that.
Wait, the mushroom is following me as well?
Okay.
Time for the treasure room.
Oh wait, we can re-roll it!
Why don't I have more money?
Many spider enemies become less dangerous.
That's actually pretty nice.
I don't mind that.
But hold on a minute.
Look at this.
We have Yes Mother, we have Spun.
What else do we have?
Conjoined?
Okay, actually, no.
We have one out of three on everything.
I think I'm gonna try and re-roll.
Mom's contacts.
Range, chance to fire, petrifying tears.
That takes us to two out of three on Yes Mother.
I think I like it.
What if I do it again?
Want to blow it up?
Okay.
Petrification is good, though.
Oh!
Man, you are fast.
You got petrified!
Petrification!
Man, I got really lucky there, I think.
I hope I didn't.
46% devil chance.
Oh, here we go.
Here we go.
What happened?
Something just went...
Wait, is...
Is that my little buddy?
Sir!
Oh, wait, he got turned evil or something.
And now I released him from his evil.
Weird.
Oh, I walked into it.
That was so bad.
I guess we're going to go for this now.
Wish me luck with the devil, the adversary.
Okay.
I don't know what you do.
Okay, are you going to come fl...
Okay, I see.
I'm scared of those red flames.
Oh, he...
Wow.
Man, the bending laser.
He's going up here.
Yeah.
Oh, God.
Are you appearing?
Okay.
No, I got hit by that.
Uh, false PhD.
Blackheart, Converse.
Oh, yeah, this one is good.
This one is good, actually.
Locked it.
Wait, why did I lose an HP there?
Wasn't I supposed to not...
You lose an HP?
What was the whole point?
Of the fucking devil's pact or whatever I did.
What the fuck?
That's bullshit.
You got to be kidding me.
I was supposed to get that for free.
Let me go back and read that.
Something's off.
What's up here?
Why did I lose a heart?
Activating this before defeating the current floor's boss will replace the boss reward with a devil deal item.
Oh, okay.
Fuck.
Ugh.
Then I should have used my goddamn coupon on it.
I thought I could save it, you know?
Oh, well.
Hey, what are you looking at?
That's right.
Okay, let's go this way and actually clear the rest.
Oh, money!
Good amount.
Patchification is huge here.
Man!
Thanks.
Yeah, I may as well do that.
All right.
Do I go in, though?
I have no guaranteed healing, so I'm not gonna do it.
I am considering taking the lockdown damage uphill.
I really wonder what luck actually does affect.
It's not here, it's here.
This way.
Like, it's gotta be the gambling, right?
At least.
The beggars.
The, um, what do you call it?
The machine that gives me words?
Yeah, let's just do it.
Give me that damage.
Actually, 0.84 damage is not bad at all.
That's a good exchange.
Necropolis.
All right, fine.
Pop up.
What the fuck was that, bro?
He popped up at the same time this guy started shooting.
Like, that was just annoying.
What the hell are the chances of that?
Fetchification is ultra good against these guys.
Actually, is there a time when it's not good?
I wonder.
Probably not.
Even this guy isn't guaranteed to get poisoned.
Poop explosion destroyed and deals 100 damage?
Uh, I don't know.
Nah, that's gonna mess me up, isn't it?
Okay, so you want bombs?
I can actually give you some.
I got you, bro.
All right.
Despite my luck.
I feel like the bomb guys always give rewards.
Like, it's very consistent with the bomb guys.
Yeah, oh my god.
Plus five bombs, explosions, damage, and concuss all enemies.
Uh, that is actually kind of a crazy combo with the poop thing in there that deals 100 damage.
Should I keep going?
Nah, I will gamble a little though.
Okay, I'm done gambling.
Aha!
I actually love the arcade.
And now I keep moving.
I gotta find more HP, though.
If I'm gonna beat this without losing one life, it's...
We gotta find HP.
Oh, man.
Oh, we got a bunch of hearts down here.
Good stuff.
No suspicious rocks in sight.
Okay, how much am I gonna get?
Oh, not bad.
Kind of getting lucky here despite my luck stat.
Can't complain about it.
That's fantastic.
Oh, god.
Oh, yay, yay!
I don't know how I didn't get hit there.
I would also call that luck, actually.
The luck is on my side.
There we go.
Bomb for me.
Oh, no, I hate you guys so much.
That was actually amazing.
I was hoping for an actual shop.
What am I gonna use my coupon on, then?
I mean, I get a lot of...
I guess I can go back to the arcade.
Did I blow everything up in the arcade?
I think I may have.
I burned the bridges.
Insanity.
Not great.
Let's go heal.
I like this do-rag.
It's kind of fitting with the monocle.
Four keys.
Ah, it's fine.
Wait, I'm scared about those freaking things in the corner.
Yep.
They're still active.
Not getting me.
Good, we gotta have to take care of those first.
Okay.
Taking a lot of damage, though.
These guys need to die first before we unleash the little guys.
Oh, shit!
Wow.
Oh, my goodness.
I think it's over.
This is the end of the line.
They keep coming!
This room was insane!
Jesus Christ.
Oh, man.
We're so close to dead here.
Yeah, I think...
Ah, we're not gonna survive this.
Yeah.
Challenge is not completed, unfortunately.
Now it's just a regular run.
Honestly, it was gonna be tough anyway.
With only two hearts.
Okay.
Let's see.
We got the coupon ready.
For what comes out...
Oh, okay, okay.
I may actually die here.
Oh, that was close.
Very close.
One HP.
Half an...
Okay, okay.
It was a good run.
What are my tears, though?
Did you see my tears?
They became sort of black green at the end.
I don't know why that was.
Okay, go again.
We gotta not waste HP like that.
That was a mistake.
Also, I think I may have...
should have kept the jump.
Because I didn't get that much use out of the coupon.
Or as much as I wanted to.
Getting good amount of coins here.
Right in time for shop.
Let's see.
Nightlight.
That's a good one, actually.
I like that one.
I may come back for it.
If I have enough money.
Okay, how am I gonna deal with this?
Yes.
Slowly is the answer.
Okay.
I'm just gonna go to the boss.
No, I'm not!
Treasure Room is right down here.
Want to be something good?
Bless me.
A Game Boy?
The Game Kit.
A temporary Pan Mac.
Did it actually say Pan Mac?
Well, that's just fantastic, isn't it?
Great start.
It's gonna be an uphill battle now.
Let me see what it did.
Grants invincibility.
Disables tears.
Contact damage.
Right.
Got it.
Interesting room.
No bombs, though.
It's the ovum.
I'm gonna take damage.
Okay, I dodged the first attack.
That's good news.
Not bad!
Did that pretty well.
Is this thing again?
Yeah, sure.
Give me a chance to get the planetarium.
Whatever that is.
I'm starting to think they don't exist.
Like, 15% chance is kind of high.
I should have seen something like that at this point.
Unless I've already seen it and I didn't realize that it was a planetarium.
Then again, I feel like I would recognize that.
It's a very distinctive place.
A planetarium, you know?
Meow, meow, meow, meow.
Eat him up.
Get up!
Oh, he came back.
Hey, not bad, actually.
I thought for sure I was gonna take damage in here.
Where is that treasure room?
Gonna shoot?
Yeah.
Wait, the Emperor is the one that teleports me, so I could go into that room up there.
And then teleport out.
Sometimes I prefer enemies that chase me than just the ones that wander around randomly.
They're just annoying to hit, you know?
Uh, no bombs.
Wild.
Not a single bomb found.
At least we have keys.
What's that?
Charm of the vampire.
Damage up, plus kills heal?
Yo, that sounds amazing!
Damn!
Not bad!
Now I just need some more heart that I can heal up, you know?
Hearts become even more important now.
Creates britches over small gaps.
50% chance to drop a pickup when taking damage?
That is actually a really good synergy with my healing now.
I need to get some more money.
Except I can't.
This level is over.
All right.
Do I save my money then?
I think...
I'm gonna have to buy this just to be safe.
We don't know what kind of boss we're gonna face.
Actually, we could spend half a blue heart.
Yeah, let's do it.
Half a... oh, no.
Please don't be all bad.
No, man.
Okay, watch.
Fuck you!
Oh, that was a waste.
Come on, Larry.
Let's do it.
I wonder if he takes more damage in the head than the rest of his body.
Actually, I don't think so.
I think he takes more damage on his tail.
He's eating the poop!
I think he just healed as well.
Well, I healed there.
Nice!
That's important.
We need that HP.
Very good, very good.
What were the other buffs from it?
Shot speed, okay.
Decent start now!
It's a very good start, actually.
I also have my Game Boy color.
Nice.
Say, ah!
This Game Boy is actually pretty dope.
It only has four charges that need to be filled.
Oh, god.
This room is a fucking killer!
Like, this is one of the hardest rooms in the game.
It is so insanely difficult.
Fuck this place, man.
I'm gonna die, I'm gonna fucking die in here.
Oh!
Wow.
Oh, no.
Not spiders!
Please.
Thank-
Jesus!
Come on.
Oh, I hate these guys so fucking much.
Their random-ass walk pattern.
Oish.
Man, I wish I could go over there and heal up.
But I can't.
Eat him!
Absolutely playing that safe.
That small of a room?
No way.
Oh, my god!
No, not this!
How am I getting all these difficult rooms in a row here?
Jesus!
He caught me off!
How are you supposed to kill them?
This is ridiculous, man!
Oh, my god.
Fucking end my life.
I'm stuck.
Fucking insane room!
Harder than any boss in the game, it's crazy.
Like, why is this happening?
Also, we lost a heart?
Why the fuck did we lose a heart?
I got no idea.
No clue why we lost a heart.
Fuck, that's tilting, actually.
Give me something good, please.
Daddy long legs.
Floats high above the room and regularly targets.
That is extremely meh.
It's actually giving me more anxiety with that shadow following me.
I wish I didn't pick it up.
Great.
I don't understand how I lost a heart.
That's pissing me off to no end right now.
It makes no fucking sense.
Placing a bomb also creates a small pool of high damaging crea- Yeah, no thanks.
Unless it's not gonna hurt me, right?
That's probably gonna hurt me.
Knowing this game.
Oh, thank you, daddy long legs.
No, we're gonna die.
Kill the tomatoes.
My shot speed is so bad.
Well, I should say tears, technically.
That's what I mean.
Okay.
Please give me more HP.
Placenta.
Okay, we have a lot of healing.
And I haven't seen the devil room in years.
Wait, why don't we just lose a bunch of stats?
No idea.
Things happen for a reason.
Teleports to an uncleared room.
Oh, that one.
I don't know if I want that.
Okay.
Counterfeit penny.
Ah, actually.
I feel like I need any help I can get in terms of damage here or combat.
I guess we'll use the thingy on it.
Energy.
Come on.
Sir.
Thank you.
Okay, I actually kind of like that guy now.
These fucking pills, dude, are going to kill me.
I've been so unlucky with the pills.
It is insane.
15 coins, though.
Wait, so what's the difference between these two?
Give me battery.
Are you always going to give me battery, the guy with the hair?
Battery and hagalas.
Okay, sure.
Dude, I don't think I found a single bomb in this entire run.
Unless I'm, you know, mixing up runs right now in my head.
It's actually insane.
Thanks, buddy.
How do I use this in a good way?
Kills or removes the armor from many stone enemies.
I don't think I know any stone enemies.
Do I know any stone enemies?
I think I'm dead.
How the hell?
This is impossible.
Whatever, dude.
Almost ran into the spikes here.
You know what actually killed me?
I don't want to do this run.
This run fucking sucks ass.
Just start it over, man.
What a waste of time.
Go again.
What a joke of a run.
That's a good start.
Give me ten coins from one poop, please.
Wait, why do I have an XL in the top right?
What does that mean?
Like, I wish the game would explain some of these fucking UI things that just happen.
What does the purple XL mean?
Uh, doctor's remote.
The targeted airstrike is actually massive.
There's also a tinted rock there.
Come on.
Oh, that guy's gonna spawn a million spiders.
Huh.
No tinted rocks in there at all.
You bastard.
Wait, minus 64 on demon.
What?
I take random damage and my demon goes down?
What is going on?
What, these fucking percentages?
It feels so fucking random.
You know, I fart on a Tuesday.
Demon goes up by 10%.
I buy a chocolate bar.
Demon goes down by 5%.
Do not shoot that green goo but me.
I knew you were gonna do it.
Last guy killed himself in the fire.
Yeah, why not?
I'm gonna air strike this guy.
Actually, not yet.
We gotta take out his little guys first.
And then we air strike him.
Wait, I got hit by the ghosts?
For some reason I thought they were gonna pass through me.
What a dance here.
Okay, here we go, here we go.
Yeah!
Oh my god.
Wait, did my balls just get bigger?
Why?
Look at my tears, they're like massive.
Nice, very good.
Okay, uh, wait, what?
Oh, it's one of those again.
Okay, we're doing more.
One, two, three, four.
Killed your baby.
Very clean so far.
Nice, uh, range lock a soul heart that is actually pretty good.
Okay, uh, I'm done here.
Moving on.
We're speed running.
We only take the good stuff and we move on.
This is now the strategy.
I see it clearly in my mind.
Also, what the fuck is going on?
I haven't seen a bomb in the last two runs.
Like actually, what the hell is happening with the bomb spawn rate?
Are you fucking kidding me?
Not a single bomb in the last 30 minutes of the game.
It is insanity.
Please die, thank you.
Dead end.
Kind of want to air strike this guy so bad.
Can I touch that?
I cannot.
Tomatoes.
Oh, come on.
Line up for me.
That's good enough.
Point.
This one's actually going to be difficult.
Yeah, good.
Yes, love when that chain reacts.
Dude, I love this little frozen baby.
One of the better familiars for sure.
It's also mega fun to just shatter the enemies.
Yeah, this room's going to kill me.
Fucking juked.
Insanity.
Okay.
I need healing.
We got to freeze him.
That was risky.
That was a little bit risky what I did there, but it's okay.
Thankfully, now I need healing.
Question, can I get it?
Okay,
that guy could be killed.
I know you want to shoot me.
Yeah, there it is.
Man, what a mess.
Come on.
Yes.
Good.
There's more?
There you are.
Okay, man, this room is crazy.
All right.
Still haven't found a single bomb, by the way.
I don't understand how it's like statistically possible what is happening right now.
Okay, give me some like amazing coins now.
I need money.
Make me rich.
Okay, well.
We're going to go into the shop with eight coins.
There's healing.
I'm buying it.
Yeah, I'm buying that.
Also, vocal bombs.
There we go.
Thanks.
Compass.
I can't afford it anyway.
You know what?
Donate some money.
I'm probably going to die in a second anyway.
I'm...
You know what?
I'm just going to give up on trying to understand this game.
I don't understand how the fuck I'm at three hearts.
I'm losing my damn mind.
I need to watch this bot back in slow motion.
Instant replay to see what the fuck is occurring in these runs.
I'm just fucking bleeding hearts here.
Finding heart pickups doesn't even matter.
Lose them anyway.
To something.
Come
on, fatty.
Good.
Hey, health up.
Doesn't matter, though.
I'm going to lose the heart anyway.
Dead cat grants nine extra lives.
50% chance to be revived with half a heart when taking lethal damage.
Fuck it.
I'm taking everything.
The problem is, though, I pretty much just have...
I was about to say nine, but 11 hearts now in total.
So when they're gone, you know, it's...
Then we're at one heart, pretty much.
And losing, like, 11 hearts in six floors is very standard, right?
Unless you can somehow keep healing at half a red heart.
But at some point, enemies start doing a full heart of damage, though, so...
Um...
Wish I could blow it up.
I need to understand what's happening here.
Did I pick something up that said, you can no longer find bombs or something?
Is that, like, a thing?
Okay, go north.
I just gained a bunch of stats.
Take my money.
Enjoy them.
Finally!
Dude, we're getting some good luck with the pills, at least.
Um...
Oh, well, I'm poor and right.
I was going to buy the blue heart.
I can't believe it!
That has to be the first bomb in 40 minutes!
Jesus Christ, what am I going to use it on?
Do I blow this guy up?
Or do I save it for a secret room?
Oh my God, it's so special.
Uh...
I'm going to go in here, though.
I have the airstrike.
Oh, no, it's useless against this guy.
Actually, the frozen enemies here could be huge.
If we could...
Oh, wait, I thought he was frozen, man.
Pfft!
I was going to punch him into the other ones.
For fuck's sake.
There we go.
Maybe you cannot freeze these little guys.
Only the very tiny guys you can freeze those.
It's for you.
Uh...
Yes, that's good.
It's very good.
Okay.
What now, though?
We haven't found the treasure room.
I need to understand something here.
So hard.
No.
Like, I am not understanding why I have so much damage right now.
None of my items are giving me damage.
I don't have any three out of three on something, right?
Two out of three on this one.
Guppy.
But there's, like, no damage.
How do I have so much damage?
I don't...
Get that.
I'm kind of hitting modifier or whatever.
Don't kill me.
I feel... I don't know what's happening today.
It's like nothing makes sense in this game anymore.
I keep losing hearts for no reason.
My damage goes up and there's no items that give me damage stats.
Like, nothing makes sense today.
I don't know what's going on.
It is so freaking confusing.
Scapular.
Uh, let's see here.
That is very good for me.
That is very good for me with the nine lives.
Well, I didn't even see that.
I wouldn't have picked it up.
Actually, let's leave now, then.
But how does that work when we have...
Yeah, how does that work, though?
With the nine lives.
Let's see, let's see.
Do we then always respawn with two hearts?
If we actually get down to zero.
So we gained a heart there.
And we lost a bunch of stats.
Now we're at 5.8 damage.
We were at 10 range before, now we're at seven.
Or maybe we were at nine before.
Maybe it is something just innately...
Lazarus.
I don't know.
Maybe Lazarus gains random stats on every floor.
That's the only thing I can think of.
I don't know.
Like, part of me wants to take notes on it, but I can't.
Because none of it makes sense.
It's so completely random.
Like, it wouldn't make any sense to take notes on any of this.
Okay, I entered this floor.
Now I lost 3.8 damage for no reason.
You know, like, it doesn't help me.
I think the worst thing I can do is...
Oh, careful.
Is write notes where I'm assuming things.
That's just gonna confuse me later.
This is crazy.
Uh, yeah.
We got an X here.
Gotta do the drive-by.
And we're gonna use this fly now.
There we go.
Okay, decent.
I wanna go back and heal.
Because I'm afraid...
Oh, no.
Like, if I hit...
If I die now and I lose one life...
I wonder if my two hearts are gonna go down to one.
I think the nine lives thing is like...
Okay, you gain an extra heart.
You can't just have that nine times now, you know?
It'll be too good.
Wait, what?
Close.
Do I go in there?
Oh, I hate this room so much.
It's like a...
What do you call it?
A speed check.
If your character's too slow, you're just gonna take damage.
Unless you have, like, insane precision.
Oh, god.
No.
I froze his balls!
Oh, you're still gonna shoot?
Okay.
Wait a minute!
I see footsteps on the floor.
Actually, there weren't real footsteps.
They were kind of fake footsteps.
They were small.
They weren't going straight into the wall like the other ones, you know?
It was a fake one, for sure.
What was that sound?
Increase the end of the fighting card.
Oh, actually, that's pretty good.
Better than nothing, at least.
Size down, speed...
Yeah, good stuff.
I like size down.
Nine...
Oh, no, it's this...
Amazing.
Now we need a proper shop so we can spend our money.
What's that?
Grant's flight!
This is going pretty good so far.
Okay, you need to calm down now.
Calm down.
Oh, we got a champion!
Dude, this room is fucking crazy.
Wow.
Nice.
Hey, that's for you!
Okay, you didn't drop anything special for me?
I don't want to spend my bombs.
Too valuable.
Oh, shit.
Keep kiting, keep kiting.
Okay.
Oh, gosh.
I'm so bad at this stuff.
And now we...
Go!
I'm happy with that.
Get bombed, nerd!
Pedrified!
Ah, damn it.
Ouija board, more...
Yes, that's actually fantastic.
Going pretty well here.
Getting some good items.
Okay, um...
Treasure room has been found.
All that is good, so we move on.
Yeah, I'm happy.
Let's pay attention to the damage now.
We're gonna get randomized stats, I think.
Something about Lazarus.
Just creates random stats.
A hundred demon mode?
Stats are the same.
Okay.
Maybe there are certain breakpoints, where if you go to, you know, floor five or something, you gain demon points.
And that always happens on floor five.
I don't know if I'm on floor five right now.
It's just a random number, right?
But...
I don't know.
It feels completely random to me, so we gotta take more data.
Uh...
No, I was gonna push the fucking thingy.
Push it!
Oh my god.
Okay, fine.
Wow.
I really want that.
But I'm not gonna get it.
Too bad.
Oh no.
Yo.
Mom's footstomp's down.
Fitting.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
We could use flight in here.
I don't know if that's worth it.
I think it may be worth it, actually, to conserve one extra life, right?
Because we're kind of close to dying.
Oh, shit.
Naughty.
Jesus Christ, this room is gonna kill me, man!
Yes.
Oh my god.
What happened there?
Something went...
What happened?
Went damage down to the last half-heart.
How is that?
Is it this one?
But I didn't gain a soulheart, though.
Let me see here.
50% chance to be re...
No, I don't know.
No idea what that was.
Yes!
That's a good one.
Game room!
I have a lot of money to spend.
I would gladly do that.
Ah, that's a little bit.
I don't like that.
Let's go get some HP in here.
This should be doable.
We got one luck!
Time to gamble.
If there ever was a time, now is it?
Actually, maybe this guy's better.
What's that?
Anisha.
Fantastic.
Ripped the map I just revealed.
That's kind of funny.
Man, what is it?
Okay.
I was about to say, with one luck, at least we got to be winning something here.
Come on.
Ah, man.
Okay, man.
What is this shitty arcade?
Come on!
Yeah, now we're talking.
More of that.
Beautiful.
The luck was just a little delayed in here.
It happens.
I am not going to make the same mistake of staying inside here and getting hit by a fly that spawns.
Remember that one time?
I have PTSD from that.
One more heart, please, before we go.
I beg you.
No.
Okay.
Guess I'm going to blow these up.
No, I'm going to gamble.
Gamble everything.
One heart.
Uno, hearto.
Man, so many keys.
This one is speed.
I like it.
I'm going to do it from here.
Watch.
Puberty.
Very good.
Now, I'm completely lost, of course.
The map has been amnesiaed.
Feels bad.
Uh, two hearts.
Yeah, why not?
This is going swimmingly.
I actually don't remember if we died once in this run.
I think we did.
So, the challenge thing of unlocking the character is lost, I believe.
That's okay.
Okay.
Man,
I'm really fast.
Oh, no.
Yeah, okay, man.
Wow.
Ice, ice, baby.
Good.
These guys are tough, so I'm just going to sit here.
So, the hagalas.
Stone enemies.
Who are the stone enemies?
Is there a boss that has stone on them?
Like, I don't recall any enemies that have, like, some sort of armor that I need to go through before I attack them.
The inner eye?
Wait, fires three tiers in a cone shape?
I think it's worth trying.
Yeah!
Definitely worth.
Very nice.
Shotgun style.
A little slower attack rate, but that's totally fine.
I think I have multiple feet coming down.
Or not.
Dude, having that speed is so good.
I think I've been sleeping on how important speed is.
You know?
Okay, hold on.
Before I go in there.
Super greed!
Oh god.
Jesus.
Like, I...
There's too many projectiles for me.
My brain can't handle it.
Wow.
I think we had some healing as well somewhere.
Creates a trap door to the next floor, or creates a crawl space of used on top of floor decoration.
Okay.
Let's hunt for some floor decoration, baby.
Like, is this floor decoration?
That's a floor decoration.
Yeah!
Fuck yeah!
Uh, sir.
Good.
Tough love.
She had to fire tooth jaws at the...
Oh!
I have one luck!
We gotta try and get more luck then.
Oh, that's so good.
Uh, so we've been to treasure room.
We've been to the shop.
Yeah, actually take this again.
What did I leave behind?
Oh, okay.
All right, let's go in and do an airstrike on this guy.
I mean, gal.
Oh yeah, not bad.
Why is mom blue?
What's happening there?
Oh, spiders.
Oh, the petrification there was huge.
Yeah, we did it.
Uh, the stapler is damaged.
Very good.
Stables Isaac's left eye shot causing all shots to be...
Yeah, that mechanic is still super weird.
Let's try and see here.
We shoot and it looks like that.
With that attack rate.
And now,
exact same.
Like, this left right eye mechanic, I'm not understanding it.
Maybe it's just flavor text, actually.
Maybe that doesn't mean anything.
It's just flavor.
You know, like it's gruesome to stable your eyes shut.
Okay, um, oh, it's open here.
The hermit.
That's for you.
Wow.
Jesus Christ, bro.
Wait, we gained a bunch of stats when we died.
Right.
So that's what either Lazarus or the Nine Lives is doing here.
The hermit.
Is there even a shop here on this floor?
I don't think there is.
Like, that's not a thing.
Yeah, look, now we have only one Red Heart.
I figured that that was what was going to happen.
So when, um, when you have the Nine Lives...
What is it actually called?
Dead cat.
So when you have dead cat, um, you get to one HP, right?
But if you then increase the amount to two or even three or four, and you then die, then you lose all that extra HP you got.
And you're back to having only one every time, right?
That's what's happening there.
Okay, give me that.
Actually, let's teleport to the shop room, because why not?
Okay, that's the shop room, huh?
This room would have been a shop if we hadn't been in, uh, the womb or the whatever this place is inside mall.
The frickin' insides and trails.
The uterus.
Man, the shotgun style here is very nice.
Really digging the triple shot.
The hanged man.
Oh yeah, I never used my old one.
Maybe this is the time to do it.
I'll come back for this if I find a room where I need to fly.
Okay,
definitely not stepping in this economy.
But kind of want to click that button.
Sometimes good stuff happens when you click the button.
Oh, the shotgun is going to be so good against these.
Yeah.
Huh?
Oh, I stepped on the frickin' spike!
Whoops.
Didn't even see that.
Okay, we got eight lives and question marks.
Wait, another one of these?
Oh right, we've been here, that's why.
Now this guy, he's on a timer.
He's going to come out anytime now.
Okay,
take it slow.
Should be easy enough.
What?!
Oh wait, we take a full heart from those now.
That explains it.
Wait, how's this guy not dying?
Okay, that's huge, I need that right now.
Get away from me.
That's for you!
Um, I guess the bomb...
I mean, the boss is this way.
Let's try not to mess this up.
And the bomb is this way.
Light save.
All right.
All right, worms!
That healing is pretty much useless, because, um...
Yeah, this is the problem with this floor and onwards.
You take a full heart, so one damage, you know, and you go down.
Healing is pretty much not a thing anymore.
Where is the boss?
The only path I didn't go...
Oh god.
Oh yeah.
Two of diamonds?
Hey!
Actually, not bad.
Now we just need to find some beggars.
Oh my god.
I don't know if we can actually win this, man.
Like, I need a lot of blue hearts.
Okay, here's the boss.
It's not mom yet.
Shit.
I guess I can't use air strike here, because...
I'm just gonna die if I stand still for more than two seconds.
Focus up.
Focus, focus, focus.
Yes!
Very good.
Black heart is huge.
We like that.
Do I care about the cards here?
That much?
I don't think so.
Ah, I don't have so many bombs already.
And maybe this is better.
Alright.
Five lives left.
This is the final level.
Oh, scary room.
Oh, man!
Come on!
Actually, one thing we do have is a lot of bombs.
We can use that to our advantage.
Just bomb the shit out of everyone.
Wait, am I pushing my bomb away?
Oops.
Okay, nice.
I want to go straight to the boss, as soon as I can.
Okay.
Don't think I want to do that.
Oh, shit!
I think we have three lives left, if I were to guess.
Not looking good.
Come on.
There you are.
Yes.
Oi, oi, oi!
Unfortunately, we took the wrong path.
That guy has so much HP.
He's a gravity man.
What the...
Oh, yeah, right.
This is so weird.
Hey, asshole!
There are the bosses.
Oh, man.
I think I have three lives.
There's no way I can dodge all those projectiles, though.
Wish me luck.
Oh, wait, it's...
It lives!
It's not even the boss I was...
I thought it was going to be.
Wait, it is kind of the boss I thought it was going to be, but it's different.
Oh, god.
Fuck me!
Nice, he's down.
He's down, he's down.
Okay, okay.
Oh, god.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Oh, wow.
No, we got to start over!
There's no way!
Okay.
Airstrike!
Huge.
Come on, deal some good damage here now!
Yeah!
Fuck, yeah, man!
Oh, wait, we can't take a chest.
We have to keep going.
Oh, no.
Oh, now it's surely over.
Oh, man.
You know what?
I kind of want to go down, actually, instead of up.
I feel like I haven't gone down in a while.
Sheol.
Okay.
We have five hearts!
Oh, shit!
I thought we had three.
Well, that's a... that's some good news.
At this again?
Bro, what?
Okay.
We need to find blue hearts.
That's the name of the game right now.
Blue hearts.
Or black hearts.
Both are good.
Our range is very good, actually.
Could play a bit of Space Invaders.
Oh, my fucking god, bro.
That is annoying.
We're gaining damage every time we die, though.
Huh.
Maybe the strategy is to go to one life left?
And then just stack up on blue hearts.
Wait, these enemies are new?
Oh, my goodness.
What happened?
Now, where could the boss be?
Oh, wow.
Oh, we didn't gain more damage.
Okay.
Fuck these enemies.
Oh, no.
Uh, you know what?
Can we blow this up?
Okay, it didn't do much.
Oh, what is it with this?
Oh, Jesus.
We need hearts.
Yeah, okay.
No, thanks.
I'm leaving.
Not for me.
There's, like, no chance we're gonna win against the...
Was that the last?
That was the last.
Okay.
Go again.
That was a good run, I guess.
I shouldn't have picked up the fucking nine lives, man.
It's bait every time.
I fucking hate that item.
In hindsight, though, I think it was the right choice to do with last run.
Simply because I didn't find any more health upgrades after that.
Only one I found.
Freezer baby, again?
Ah, too risky.
Actually, now it's good.
Yeah, that's good.
I kind of wish I got a different item, like...
I just had this item.
Okay, we're gonna try and pay attention now, by the way.
What happens when we die?
Are we gonna get more damage?
If we are gonna get more damage, then we confirm that it's Lazarus related.
I think it is.
It's what makes the most sense to me.
Wait, this is so slippery.
Look at this.
Come on, now.
Gonna charge me?
No.
It's a box stuff.
I'm excited.
The sun is actually pretty good.
This is also pretty decent.
That's funny.
Ew, ew.
Okay, speed, speed, speed, speed.
Speed rod!
Freeze him!
Freeze him all!
We go fast.
Because we are in a little box now, like a car box.
Wheel of fortune.
Blow it up.
Take this.
Take it.
Move!
Okay, that's a dead end.
Leaving.
Find the boss, find the boss, and eliminate.
Eliminate, eliminate.
Kill, kill, kill, kill.
Okay, that's good.
Okay, we got item here.
That's a good one.
We like that one.
Go!
Okay, we can grab this.
Faster!
See ya, nerd.
Oh, look at the speed!
Jesus Christ.
Why did I run into that?
Oh, wait, I don't even have enough money to buy that.
That's too bad.
Nah, I don't want anything there.
Ah, we don't have time to do that.
We gotta go, we gotta go.
I thought I could get in without taking damage.
I was wrong.
Turned out to be worth it, though.
That's for you.
Go, go, go!
The boss has to be here.
Yep.
That's a bomb.
Lovely.
Go!
Bomb him!
Missed!
Bomb for you!
That's for you!
Oh my god.
Kidding me.
Man, these spiders are killing me.
No!
I got hit by the fucking projectile!
You gotta be kidding me!
And we lost our heart.
Okay, so I guess it's...
Confirmed that when you lose HP, or when you die, you lose a heart.
Faster, faster!
Oh no, not this.
Okay, that's good, that's good.
Son!
Why are they so annoying?
Good.
The Hierophant, that's good.
Grab it, grab it, and go.
This is for you!
Kill him.
Uh, yeah, give me.
The magnet is good.
Allows me to grab items.
We don't have time for this.
We gotta move, we gotta move, we gotta move.
We gotta be home for Christmas.
Nice.
Go in.
Six coins.
That's not great.
Good enough to buy this, though.
Thank you.
Go!
We're husking!
Keep freezing the enemies.
Yes!
Massive.
Glass eye.
Moving on.
Go!
Look, the timer's behind us!
We're catching up!
Ice, ice baby.
For you!
Quick, quick, quick, quick, quick, quick.
This way for sure.
Uh, two of hearts.
I guess we'll spawn them here, I guess.
Oh wait, I thought there was the one that spawned them on the floor.
Go, go!
Uh, shoot the move!
We love that one!
Great item!
Wow.
Keep moving.
Oh god.
Stop that, sir.
That's for you!
I see orange.
Dude, I love the magnet.
Magnet is good.
Do I do this?
Yeah.
Shit!
Get out!
Oh, I couldn't precision it.
I was out of time.
Huge.
Spider baby!
Or Spider Monamine.
That's a massive upgrade.
We gotta find more HP though, like an actual HP upgrade.
Otherwise, none of this is gonna matter.
Look, they're stuck!
I got a little scared.
I used it.
We're gonna clear another room and then boss.
And we're gonna shoot the whoopid.
Nice.
Don't care about that coin.
Let's go!
We're shooting and we're whooping.
Holy shit!
Well, that was fast.
Man, the shoot did more damage than I thought it would.
Damn, we don't get any HP!
Um...
Well, I can't take that, right?
Did I die?
Not that I wanted anyway, fuck it.
Go!
The timer's behind us!
Uh, I predict south.
Oh my god, the gravity's...
Okay, keep going.
Okay, we can grab this, I guess.
Gotta be fast.
Uh, no way we're stepping.
Whoa!
This way...
Oh my god, treasure room!
Oh, fuck.
No!
Uh...
Like, aren't there supposed to be a million items in this game?
I get the same items every run!
Ice baby and the fucking knuckles?
Like, give me something new.
Why is he small?
Oh no!
Oh, this is gonna be so difficult.
Kill him, kill him, kill him.
Nice.
Wait, what's in here?
Oh, it's the button, okay.
Like, where's my HP at, dude?
Dude, I feel like every single freaking run in this game right now is the ultimate struggle.
Are you gonna shoot at me?
I didn't even see that coming.
Wow.
All right, I've had enough of losing.
Watch me get flying and all the items now.
All
right, there's...
Besides unlocking that one character with Lazarus, there's like no reason to play the other characters.
It doesn't make any sense.
They are unbelievably under tuned compared to this guy.
Thanks!
We love that one.
Actually, I'm gonna go in here.
Because I have the fool, right?
Come on, come on.
Take me back.
What is with the balance in this game?
Like, it is just not balanced.
Thank you.
What's that?
Split shot?
That's fucking awesome!
Let me see what else it did.
Okay.
Very nice.
I priestess.
I don't know if I should go fast this time.
Like,
something I've noticed.
In the beginning of the game, I donated so much money to that shop.
I feel like I can't do that anymore.
Like, I just...
I need every single coin nowadays.
Midnight snack, thank you for the HP.
Wait, oh yeah.
Okay, there's two bosses this time around.
Okay.
And we get a turtle heart, and a box, and devils!
I mean, here we go.
I didn't mean to use that, actually.
That was a mistake.
Lock up!
Wow!
Just take it all, dude.
A walnut?
What is that?
Being hit by an explosion has a chance to destroy the trinkets.
Fantastic.
Love it.
We go in here.
Oh, shit.
Okay.
Little brimstone.
Dark matter!
Chance for tears to apply fear.
Chance increases with luck.
We have good luck right now.
Why not?
I like it.
We're gonna gain an extra heart now, because of eternal.
Oh, yeah, right.
I can just sit it here.
I like the little poop we have on our head.
Beautiful.
Little tiny antennas.
That is an amazing item.
Thank you.
Oh, I really want those pills.
Need money.
What is that one?
Pokego plus one fly orbital.
That's a pretty good one, actually.
I don't mind that.
Wait, why am I able to see that anyway?
Do I have an item that allows me to see what tears are gonna be?
Is it this one?
Oh, yeah, it is.
Wait!
I thought this was the false PhD!
Converge bad pill effects into their good counterparts.
Identifies pills before using them.
That's what doing it.
This one's a pill on pickup.
Donating blood grants more coins.
Amazing.
Fucking hell, dude.
Love that.
One more.
Thanks.
What's that?
New item!
Yes!
More blood.
Deals instant damage to all enemies in the room.
The damage dealt is equal to I6 tier damage plus 10% of the enemy's max health.
Chance to also spawn a half red heart.
That sounds amazing!
Bro!
Getting all the new items here.
Instead of the same items, every single fucking run on the other characters, like...
Azazel is just infinitely more fun to play.
Look at this!
A child, please!
Familiars follow more closely.
Familiars gain a 1.25x damage multiply.
Abba, wait a minute.
This may actually be bad for me.
Because I want this fly orbital to block damage for me.
But does that count as a familiar?
I'm actually not sure.
I think I'm gonna leave that on the floor.
Yeah.
I think that's the right choice.
Let me try this.
Okay, it did a little damage to them, I guess.
Oh, this one!
Do I want that?
What did I have now?
Being hit by an explosion has a chance to give me some stuff.
Nah, let's get this.
It's too situational.
Oh!
Oh, I think I got hit by one of his attacks.
Didn't even see it at all.
Okay, I guess we do the boss.
Wait, wait, wait.
So this is a very narrow room.
I wonder if I can even destroy a wall there.
Yeah, there's no secret here.
Uh, where would it be?
I don't know.
Let's move on.
Oi!
Sir, what are you doing?
A devil deal!
Range and a red heart.
Well, I don't think I should be taking a deal here.
Unless it's really good.
I mean, that one is pretty good.
But that leaves me with one black heart.
That may be a little too risky.
Even for me.
Oh, no.
Well, now I'm definitely not taking it.
Absolutely not.
Man, my range is getting kind of crazy here.
Yeah, leave it.
We got to find some more pills.
That's the name of the game right now with the PhD.
Do I gamble?
I can give you some bombs, I guess.
Boom.
Hey, thanks for the bombs.
I'll take this back.
I'm looking for a blue heart or something.
Actually, I'm going to stop at five.
Saving it for a shop.
Maybe there's like a blue heart that costs five, you know?
I got to play Mega Save here because my HP is super low.
Wait, sometimes my tiers are like not doing the shift.
And sometimes they are.
It's a little bit weird how that works.
You see that?
I guess it's aiming for the enemies or something.
Batteries?
At least I need this.
Oh, shit.
That's kind of scary.
I came from there.
I would like to get some more tiers so I can charge up faster.
My charge is definitely a little slow right now.
Be good to me.
Fruitcake, every tier fires a random...
I mean, that's fun.
Wait, that broke some stuff.
Did you see that?
I guess that was acid on that.
Oh, this is going to be chaotic.
The stars.
Teleport to the treasure room.
If there is a planetarium, teleport to it instead, please.
No.
Okay, so I guess there is no planetarium.
It doesn't exist.
It's not real.
Electricity.
There's an electricity effect there.
I don't think I want to buy.
Look at that thing!
Take all my money.
You can have it.
Okay.
Whoa!
Wait a minute.
Where's the arcade?
We got to go back to the arcade and spend all our money.
We got to get some blue hearts.
Yes, we are rich all of a sudden.
This way.
Oh, that's kind of a detour.
I could also look for some secrets.
I have a lot of bombs.
In fact, I suspect there may be a secret.
Oh, never mind.
I was about to say right here.
Okay, take my money, man.
I need blue hearts or black hearts.
I mean, more money is also okay.
He's going to spawn a bomb and he's going to kill him.
These are actually pretty good, too.
Oh, shit.
Wait, what just happened there?
Destroy all breakable obstacles.
I think I should keep death.
I'm not sure.
I think both are probably around the same.
It's going to be annoying to walk into, though.
Go from the side.
Come on, man.
I need something good here.
Something good.
Whoa, that's cool.
Whoa, glad I wasn't standing close to that.
Uh, take it.
Spiders, huh?
Whoa.
Uh, death or hog?
I'm going to keep hog a loss.
Man.
Okay, secret here.
Man, okay, here.
Oh, man.
I will find it.
No matter what.
He can't hide from me.
Five bombs left.
Maybe it will hide from me.
Oh, there's also a room here.
The range
is kind of messing me up a little bit.
Whoa.
Uh, spawn three move.
Yeah, okay.
I mean, pretty good, I guess.
Whoa.
They woke up.
What's happening?
These guys are alive.
Blow them up.
Holy smokes.
Keep blowing them up.
Okay.
Man, I have scoured this map for blue hearts.
There are none.
I did my best.
Maybe a couple more bombs to try and look for a secret room.
But other than that, maybe here, actually.
There wasn't anything up here.
Oh, wait, right.
I have this room.
Fucking hell.
Fuck.
Oh, shit.
This one is Grant's one soul heart at the start.
Yes.
And this one was Grant's a following familiar with a randomized appearance.
I buy it all.
I take that too.
Yeah, donate the rest.
We got to get some money in this donation box.
Okay, there we go.
It broke.
I'll roll it.
I'm going to kill this guy too.
Okay.
Still no blue hearts, though.
Where is this secret room?
Oh, maybe it's up here, actually.
Hold on.
I think I know where it may be.
Right here.
Okay, I'm saving my last bomb.
Man, that's an elusive secret room.
Crazy.
Wish me luck.
I'm actually trying hagalas against this guy.
Hagalas.
Oh, what are you doing?
Okay.
Oh, wait.
What happened to my charge up?
Whoa!
Lost all my black hearts now.
Yeah, we got another health.
That's huge.
Do I waste it, though, in here?
Oh, crap!
Oh, no.
All right.
Good night, sir.
What do you got for me?
A lump of coal.
Ah!
There's an enemy!
Fucking hell!
Where'd you come from?
You must have been one of the skulls.
Makes tears increasing damage in size.
Sure.
I don't think that actually affects me.
Look at this comet.
I'm sort of...
or eyeball I'm shooting.
Uh, we heal up first.
Okay.
Go!
Two health is pretty good.
One was disastrous.
Two is okay.
Three would be stellar.
Imagine a converter now.
Ooh, yeah, baby.
This is a good pill?
Stellar!
Nice.
I'm not gonna go in there.
Hey, it's gross.
Flatworm, tears are 50% wider.
Wait, how's that work for me?
Does it even have any effect?
I don't think it does.
Yeah, it's about the same.
That is so needed.
Dude, I don't even know what's happening!
Fuck me, my screen is filled with all kinds of crap.
Eowas.
That's good.
We look for...
Wait, there's two Eowas.
No, that's a Jera.
Duplicates all chests and pickups.
Whoa!
Okay, we gotta remember that.
Floor decoration.
Let's see.
I don't see any here.
Nothing obvious at least.
Maybe that one.
That looks like a floor decoration to me.
Yeah!
Okay, I guess there's a lot of floor decorations.
Okay, that one is pretty good.
Nice synergy with my trinkets.
Now I can go pick up the other...
What are these guys called, runes?
I think these are called runes.
Daddy...
Oh, that's the one I had last run.
Or the run before last run.
Another one.
The Hagalas.
Let me actually try it in here.
Yeah, okay, it does exactly what it says.
Abundance.
So, abundance in here.
It says chests and pickups.
So, it's not gonna work on mom's coin purse and stuff, right?
Let's try.
Yeah, okay.
I figured...
This is gonna be so good.
Range...
What is that?
Pay to play.
Five coins?
Doors and objects that normally rip...
Ah...
That is not a good combination with my money equals power.
Oh god.
But I guess it's plus five coins?
Nah, I have 11 keys.
I gotta use those.
I could donate a little bit of...
Nevermind.
I think we just go.
Oh, he was petrified.
I mean, that's just crazy there.
He got frickin' smacked.
Let's go find some secret rooms, finally.
Okay, this active I have is actually doing less damage than I thought it would.
Justice...
Okay.
Yes.
I think I'm fast enough.
Now we gotta think about where the secrets are.
More speed.
Look at that chest, though.
What if I come from the top?
No, I still...
That's very needed.
That is so needed, actually.
Being able to charge up faster.
So that opened now!
Why?
Why did it open?
This is actually such a mystery with these doors.
I mean, I don't even have the faintest clue.
You like lasers, huh?
I got those too.
Okay.
We're pretty much done here.
Wait, wait, wait, actually, we have a bunch of healing.
Should we go step a little bit?
There's a stepper here.
Oh, it's a full heart.
That's two.
Let's go heal.
Here.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
I want this.
And up here, and then right.
Ah,
I need to find another half a heart.
Not a full one.
If I can.
Wait, what are these?
Sponsored blood?
Oh!
Ha!
Temperance.
I mean, it's going to give me coins.
But I kind of want to give my health to the step instead.
What's that one?
Another temperance.
Okay.
In this case, I'm going to blow that up.
I guess I'll take the pay to play.
Fine, I'll take this.
I really don't want to, but I'm taking it.
So let me actually review here.
Let's see.
So we are at two now.
I'm going to feel blessed, and then something random, I think.
And then blessed, and then...
Yeah, we'll see how it goes.
The more data we get on this, the better, right?
Down, down, down.
Okay.
Stop that.
That's rough.
Not even a...
You feel blessed?
Let's take this heart.
Do I have any more healing?
One more.
Oh, I had a half a heart here.
Okay, so now I got to be careful.
I'm actually going to go blow up the other machine here.
Blow this guy up.
I'm not going to take it yet, though, obviously.
I think I'm going to step once more.
Uno, stepo.
Prendo.
So now I feel blessed on five.
That's weird.
Hold on.
Angel spawns.
Well, it could all be super random, though.
That's the thing, right?
We don't really know.
Last time I got a bunch of hearts out of it.
Okay.
Here's the plan.
I will keep going.
I'm going to grab the hearts and the black heart, and we're just leaving.
Oh, wait!
We're healing with placenta!
Wait a minute.
No, no, I'm not going to...
No, no, come on.
It's too much.
That would be too crazy, wouldn't it?
Actually, I'm kind of tempted to.
Money is power, right?
From now on, we save.
We save everything now.
We're going to get so rich.
Let's do this.
Wow.
Now, that chest right there, it's going to cost me half a blue heart.
It's fine.
Wow.
Wait a minute.
That was an item in there that I missed.
We
can step again.
Let's keep it in mind.
Let's see, what is this?
Answers, yes!
Show me.
Okay, secret time, baby.
Huh?
Did I misalign that?
Okay, I did.
Now, this room is kind of weird.
Lot of money, though.
It's power.
Play-Doh cookie.
Right.
That's going to be interesting.
Man, it's going to be one hell of a disco we're going to have here.
Oh, I think I just had acid effect.
I could go in here.
No, not with the black heart.
Absolutely not.
I'm scared.
Don't hurt me.
Where's the last coin?
It's up there?
I thought I could get it without taking damage.
Man, look at all these runes.
And other answers.
Awas?
Dude, let's see here.
Floor decoration.
What's an obvious one?
This one is obvious, right?
Awas.
Yeah.
Oh my god, all the money.
We're going to get so much damage.
Lighter.
Chance when flake burn on an enemy.
Chance increases with a lot.
I mean, do we even want this penny or whatever this is?
I mean, it is good.
Now, we're going to keep this.
We're going to collect so many coins and become insanely powerful.
This is the plan.
It's a good plan.
What's that?
It's a chance to fire a tooth shot.
Ooh, nah, man.
But that doesn't really...
I don't think that actually works with my laser setup.
In any case, it's not fast enough.
Oh god.
I am speedy.
That's huge.
Boss has dropped two items.
Okay, I got to take this.
Tarot cloth.
Doubles the effect of most cards.
Spawns two beggars.
Okay.
Do I want to give them anything?
I guess I can give this guy a little bit of health.
I have some healing scattered.
I don't get anything for that?
Aw, man.
That's crazy.
I'm going to go heal up first.
Extra careful.
Good.
And we got answers for the next level.
Where are we going?
I'm going to grab this half heart.
Super optimization right now.
Thanks.
Time for secret room.
Okay.
No.
We need more money.
More money.
Let's go, mom.
Wait, why was she stuck like that?
Plus one health is massive.
We like that.
Okay, the book of Belial and I have the occult.
Damage range, less shot speed, tears can be controlled.
Wait, what?
Wait, how is that going to work with me?
Oh, I don't know, man.
I can find myself in this situation, I think, where I take this.
I'm going to be on two red hearts and I'm going to be in the late game soon.
I'm going to skip it.
I'm doing the adult thing here.
Really wanted to take it, but also I can't, you know?
Sometimes it'd be like that.
I'll take that.
Oh, what do we have here?
Two of hearts.
Um, answers.
You want coins?
You're not getting them.
I will blow you up.
I take coins, because it's damage.
Forgot to pre-charge.
That was a mistake.
More range.
I feel like there can come a time when you have too much range.
You know what I mean?
What is even happening here?
Like, holy crap.
My tiles go crazy.
Wow.
Damn, son.
Jesus.
What is Jaira?
That's the one that doubles, right?
Yeah, double is...
Man, if I find like a black heart now or a blue heart, I'm going to double it, I think.
Wow, he got blown the sh- Wow, wow, wow, wow, wow, wow, wow,
wow.
Money is power.
Money is good.
I think I'm getting blood drunk, guys.
This is not a good sign.
It means I'm going to start playing reckless.
Gimme.
Hey!
Man, it's so nice to have answers, you know?
I don't have to worry about where there's a secret room.
It's just there, it's nice.
I do have a bit of healing.
Huh?
What's that?
HP plus speed up!
Holy shit.
Damn.
All right.
Great.
Very nice.
And a new item as well.
Shot speed, not going to do anything for me.
But okay.
Thanks for the assist, spider.
I mean, this...
I am very powerful right now.
This is next level stuff right here.
I'm at 94 coins, dude.
We even have this, the world.
We can use that for the next level.
Actually, go here first.
What's that?
Attempts a chance to spawn a bot now.
Not interested in that.
Bible tracked!
Chance increase defining internal...
Oh!
I mean, we are reaching the end of our coin adventure.
Why not?
Switch it out.
Yeah, I like it.
Oh, wait, it was up here.
All right.
Okay, hold on.
I think I'm going to do this.
Imagine I can get like...
Nice.
Like a lot of red hearts just to lie around here.
We can go step, you know?
I know I'm sacrificing damage here.
But we have two luck right now.
Just one more reward.
Get a baby pet, it will cheer you up.
Maybe I should read these.
Your troubles be many.
Okay.
Okay, you know what?
No more money for you.
I'm going to blow you up.
You have ripped me off.
That was a bad thing to do there.
That's the boss.
What's that?
Chant to fire tears that adds our piercing and spectral chanting.
Okay, that's useless for me.
Let's do this.
Mr. Fred!
That's a new boss!
I've never seen that!
He has all these slaves.
Alright, fire rate is useless.
That's good.
What?
What is this?
Hookworm, tears travel in a squid.
Wait, this is a trinket, right?
Let me see how that looks.
Oh, that's actually...
Oh, that's pretty cool.
We gotta go with that.
That's dope as hell.
Love it.
Alright, moving on.
Okay, we gotta play safe now to conserve the black hearts.
Man, my tears look insane when I shoot them.
I don't think I've had tears as insane as this before.
This is some next level stuff.
Oh, did I just get hit?
I think I got hit by something.
What is that black worm?
Wow.
The hagalas.
Oh, let's use the world here, actually.
Forgot I had that.
Secret here.
Pills.
Yeah.
Lock.
Oh my god, three lock now.
More range.
Fuck yeah.
And a pill.
More range.
I mean, we are frickin' rolling right now.
Strength, uh, the full...
Let's see here.
And I have hagalas.
Do I want to use that first?
I mean, I guess I can use the full to, um, go into this room here.
Uh, on the right side.
More cards.
Three red hearts.
Teleport to the boss room.
If the boss room isn't cleared, grants a soul heart.
Yo!
But wait, we're gonna spawn this.
Do we have a stepper somewhere?
No, we ain't got a step!
No, step anywhere.
Oh, that's so unfortunate.
We have so many hearts.
Um...
I think I'm gonna do the emperor.
Yeah.
Oh wait, that's mom, isn't it?
Then I can't go back.
We should not do that.
Not yet.
Fuck.
I was gonna use my full.
I fucked it up.
Totally forgot.
Ah, but we can do this?
Not that it's gonna matter, I guess.
We have so much money anyway.
Yeah, we're full on money.
Okay, I guess it's not worth it.
Load up.
Unless something else comes out of it.
Randomly, you know?
Oh wait, we're full on money.
Which is such a weird thing to say.
What a weird room!
Nothing at all in there.
Actually, there's a sort of mini boss room down here.
All right, well he died.
Let's Isaac throw a poison bomb.
I guess it's better than the sharp straw.
I feel like the sharp straw is terrible.
Give me that instead.
I think I also had a strength card somewhere, maybe down here.
Honestly, I don't think it's gonna matter right now.
All
right, give me that.
School bag!
Okay, well in that case...
Going back to grab it again.
Thanks.
That one.
Okay, time for the boss.
Here we go!
It lives!
The heart is alive!
Or something.
I mean, that damage is pretty good.
Okay, we're definitely going up though.
We're going up here, we're going up.
I could have gone down, but I'm going up.
Holy fucking shit, my tears are...
out of control right now.
I don't even know my own strength.
This is where we're at.
Oh, wow.
Oh, you want coins?
I can maybe oblige, but not yet.
I gotta find some first to make sure I can stay at 99.
Let's not walk into that.
Yeah!
That is huge.
Sick.
Oh, I should have used the Emperor before, actually.
Huh?
What happened?
Oh, no way.
We got a tiny dude up here.
Head of the keeper.
Tears that hit enemies have a 5% chance to spawn a...
I mean...
More coins for me.
So that means I'm going to go back now and donate some money to that guy.
He wasn't here, he was back here.
The great donationing is happening now.
We have free luck as well.
There's got to be some blue hearts in it for me, right?
Or even red hearts.
Yeah!
Now, I don't want to use all of my coins, of course.
So this is going to add up with the damage.
The next heart I get, I'm going to stop.
Oh, a new item!
Bumbo wants coin!
Huh?
Wanders around consuming coin pickups from the ground.
Levels up as it consumes coins, gaining new abilities that can damage enemies and spawn items.
What?
That sounds amazing.
Oh, we got the shoot though!
Definitely taking the shoot.
Not even a question.
Although, is the shoot even good now compared to my attack?
Whoa!
Magic 8-ball.
Well, Planetarium, sure, but they don't exist.
Strength is good.
I'll keep that, I think.
Strength is very good.
Shot speed up.
Careful.
Pick them up!
He's getting fat!
Look at that!
Amazing.
Little fatty.
Okay, uh, definitely killing this stuff.
Come on.
Oh, shit.
Oh, I...
Oh, nice.
Did he get fatter?
Wait!
Enemies are spawning!
We gotta be more careful.
Where is the boss?
I guess I could use the Emperor.
It is somewhere, but I'm not gonna.
We're supposed to deal up here.
No, wrong way, wrong way.
What am I doing?
I feel like my shoot may not be that good, actually.
Eat him!
Yeah.
Okay, there's the boss.
I don't know what's happening.
Three blue flies.
Okay.
We got the strength.
Let's do this!
So we got, uh, shoot.
I'm gonna use that.
We're gonna strength, and then shoot, and then shoot the boob.
Wish me luck.
Whoa.
Oh, I forgot to use strength.
Oh, I thought I dodged that.
Wow, he died so fast.
We're gonna get the next part of the story here.
Like, you roll with Isaac, you get a win.
That's just how this game works.
You pick any other character, it's just so much worse.
It's crazy.
Um...
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Whoa, we got another piece!
I was afraid of, uh, this...
Maybe this wouldn't happen.
I thought that if I went up to whatever...
The cathedral, right?
That I wouldn't get the other corners.
Like, I had to, uh, you know, go back down to hell.
And kill Satan first, and then fill it up.
But it doesn't look like I need to.
Okay, um...
Let's actually try greed mode again.
I haven't done that in a while.
Let's try with Eulith!
Why not?
Let's see if I remember how this works.
So we double our minions with that, right?
Okay, two black hearts, one red.
We have this room.
Uh...
I mean, that's...
Yeah, okay.
All right, he shoots from those.
Oh, that's just gonna be...
Gonna take some getting used to here.
Not bad.
Can I- I don't think I can get in there without taking a hit.
Three items, they're all pretty good, actually.
All right, let's go.
Wait, there's no way you can kill things before the timer runs out, though.
Not with this character.
Oh, man.
Spider nest!
Okay, it's down.
Oh, fuck me, they keep coming.
Okay, not bad, actually.
Space invaders.
Upside down space invaders.
No problem.
Right, okay, so wait a minute.
I'm not sure what the best order of operations is here.
Okay, so what do I want?
Reveals icons for nearby special rooms?
That's not useful for me, actually.
Now, this one, one additional item will appear in treasure rooms.
That's a good one.
I feel like I may want this...
The earlier, the better, right?
And then we have...
Ooh, look at that one.
Looks like a mining pick from Minecraft.
Interesting.
We could also save up for a key, I guess.
There you are.
Duplicate.
Okay, going pretty well.
Sick.
Oh, there's more.
I have my minions, too.
He has his flies, I have my little guys here.
Sick.
Wait, we have 13 coins, though.
Would love to buy the stapler, actually.
Okay, I'm gonna go for this one.
Yep.
Okay, uh...
Ooh, that one is so good!
So, apparently, if I take this, it's not gonna get saved, right?
This is the problem.
So, I don't even know what it does, but I guess I could write it down.
Let me try it.
2020.
Oh.
Okay, fires two tiers at a time.
Ah, not bad!
That's pretty good.
Honestly, that's an easy one to remember.
I'm not gonna forget this one.
Because it works with the bookworm, it's the same logic, right?
Bookworm, you gain glasses, and you suddenly shoot two tiers.
Wait, wait, before I click that...
I have 15 now!
Oh, man.
I gotta try a new item.
Data Miner, 109.
Visually distorts entities in the room, grants a small stat increase or decrease, and grants the fruitcake effect for the room.
Item pedestals are rerolled into glitched items.
What the fuck does that even mean?
Wha- Ehh, okay!
Stairway?!
Wha- what?!
Haha, wait, wait, wait, what?
Where's my, uh...
Oh no, oh no!
No, give me my fucking box back!
Oh, this is...
I think it's bugged, guys.
Yeah, this is bugged.
But intentionally, 87 coins for that one?
Alright, I guess we're clicking this now.
Oh, man, that sucks ass!
This is what I get for trying new things.
This is why I always get the cheeseburger at McDonald's and nothing else.
I never try new things.
Because I know what I'm gonna get, you know, and I know I'll like it.
Oh, these guys just can't die, it seems.
Hello?
Come here.
Oh my god.
Well, that's not good.
Imagine if we had two babies right now shooting.
Life would be great.
What the hell?
Okay, we can sacrifice our hearts.
Wait.
Wait a minute.
It says I have 100% angel.
But there's no angel.
Maybe the next one will be 100% angel if I don't do it.
Like, 100% angel.
Yeah, I'm just gonna move on.
I don't think I want to buy any...
No, I don't have any money anyway.
We're moving.
Go, go, go.
Oh, leaf.
I don't want to get hit by that.
Oh look, there's a little item of greed at the end.
Or icon.
Okay, what do we have here?
Give me something good.
Wait, this counts as well?
Even these rooms have two items now I can choose.
I'm definitely going for dog.
Yeah.
Give me HP, baby.
Zero keys.
No bombs.
Is that one?
Doubles the effects of most active item activations.
Wait, what is the point even of this thing?
Grants a small stat increase or decrease.
And grants the fruitcake effect.
Okay, but it's just for the room.
That's so weird.
Whiplurm, honestly, Whiplurm would be pretty good.
I'll consider it.
Oh god.
Come on, kill him fast.
Oh, there's also stuff down there.
Wow.
Oh no.
Dude, I'm in trouble here.
I can't kill these guys fast enough.
Every time I'm not playing Azazel, all I can think is I wish I was playing Azazel.
It's what this game has become.
There's just too much crap in this room here.
Oh my god, I'm dying.
Oh my goodness.
Oh no, he's back behind the mushroom now.
Holy crap.
18 coins.
I'm honestly not intrigued by any of this that we have here.
Like at all.
Maybe that one.
Yeah.
And then we got a...
I guess I got to get a key.
Even though I really wanted to get the healing, I want to get in here.
Okay, a Harlequin baby.
Familiar?
We need familiars.
Yes.
And that one is...
Oh, they're both really good.
Oh no.
Shit.
We got to get familiars.
Okay, there's split pattern, that's kind of annoying me a little bit.
Okay, so we're going to click here.
We're going to try this pickaxe now, see what that does for me.
Maybe it's good, I don't know.
Oh, I should have paid attention to whether or not I got a stat increase.
This is going to be confusing, isn't it?
Oh,
he's almost dead.
We got him.
Oh, there's more.
Wait, what the hell is happening to my tears?
My tears are shooting crazy things.
The randomized effects here are going crazy.
All right, now we got to be on the lookout.
Don't die in a dumb way now.
Good.
Solid.
Go hide.
Hide.
Nice.
Not bad.
Damn, this is so messed up.
This is crazy.
All right, well...
Oh, I want the midnight snack real bad.
Can we get it?
Let me see.
You can click on the button again.
I don't know if we're going to get enough though.
Really want to heal as well.
Oof.
Ah, we got to fight again.
Hello?
Oh, okay, we got two of them.
Focus, focus, focus.
Yeah!
Angel!
Oh, what's this?
A new item!
Crown of Light.
The untainted gain power.
Plus two soul hearts when all red hearts are full.
Tears become diamonds and deal double damage.
Taking damage removes the effect for the room.
Damn!
Okay, we got to...
We got to take a picture of that, huh?
Wait, why did it do that?
No, no, no, I need to...
Oh, my shit is bugging out.
Okay, there we go.
That works.
What the...
I'm trying to take a screenshot of this shit.
Doesn't work.
Okay, well, Crown of Light.
I'm just going to ride it somewhere.
Let's see here.
I'm just going to ride glowing crown, because this is not going to get saved, right?
Glowing crown.
Insane!
That's all I need to know.
Take it when you get it.
And now, I really want to go heal up, so we have full red hearts.
So now, we shoot like this.
Haha!
Wait!
My little piece of shit familiar doesn't shoot diamonds.
No!
I'm robbed!
Oh, well.
Maybe the split shot thing is messing with it, you know?
Or speedage.
Wait, my range is pretty good already, right?
It could be better.
This also deals minor contact damage.
Shh.
Spun.
Speed is actually, we need speed.
Give me that.
Range is fine.
Sweet.
Oh, yeah!
Every coin matters here.
Let's see what the dealio is.
We've got poops!
Unfortunately, no coins.
All right, well, I can also re-roll if I need to.
The diamond shots!
Wait, I wonder how the diamond shots are gonna work with a sasle.
Probably isn't gonna work, right?
No!
I took damage!
My diamonds!
Mintiamondus!
It's such a tragedy.
Wait, what are these black balls?
Okay, this is gonna be problematic.
I don't have enough range.
Oh, god.
Holy crap.
Okay, space and beta time.
Except they're on me!
Nice.
Good stuff, good stuff.
25 coins, hell yeah.
So, okay, we're full health.
I don't think I want anything from here, except the key.
The key is good.
And then maybe we do a re-roll in here.
Uh, polydactyl.
Two card.
Nah, that's bullshit.
Doc- Oh!
Wait.
Well, okay.
I don't know if the diamond effect is overwritten now, or if it's still inherent in the bomb.
Do the bombs deal double damage?
Because that's gonna hurt!
If that's the case.
Okay, let's re-roll.
Okay.
Duplicates all pickups and item pedestals in the room.
No.
Mom's coin purse, random pills.
This one...
Let's get this one.
It's a familiar, right?
Giant spiders and- Oh no, it's not.
Blue flies and spiders do double damage.
Flying spider familiars do increase- No.
No, that sucks ass.
It's horrible.
I thought it was good.
Okay, here we go.
Glitch!
Glitch the shit out of- Wait, what the- Load his chest though!
Oh wait, we're using bombs.
That's right.
This is a mess!
Oh no.
I feel like I'm not dealing any damage here.
Oh yeah, there we go.
What the- What?!
Excuse me!
Hello!
Ma'am?
I'm here.
Yeah, brother!
He's cutting me off!
Man, get these fucking skulls out of here!
Losing my mind.
What's alive?
Oh, you!
You little piece of shit.
Oh, I need keys.
Oh, what a mess this is.
Look at the mess I've made.
That's horrible.
I guess I'll take a key.
Another key.
Sick!
Wait, did he just eat my heart?!
Underwear.
Need more keys.
Keep me!
Keep me now!
Okay.
This run is...
A mess.
Like this- I have no expectations of winning anything here.
This is just for the lulz at this point, because everything is just completely messed up.
Everything that could go wrong has kind of gone wrong.
Oh!
Oh, you ate it and made it black!
Which one of you did that?
Who did that?
Is it...
Wait, who's doing that?
Not that one.
Maybe it's that way.
Or that one, I don't know.
The stairway?
Okay.
Sure.
Stop.
We're gonna blow everything up in here.
Fuck this shop.
I hate that I'm blocking my own shots, because I'm running in front of it, you know?
Oh, hell yeah.
Yeah.
I'm gonna save the rest.
Okay, so let's see here.
Soul hearts is good.
Makes tears increase and that's useless for me.
I like this.
I need soul hearts.
Here we go.
Oh, that shit on the floor!
Please die.
Thank you.
Oh, oh shit, he's fast!
Oh my god!
Shit is crazy!
Oh no.
Not the eyes!
How are you hitting me?
Insane.
This is actually insanity.
Oh, what the hell, man.
Well, I gotta...
You know what?
It would be amazing to have one of those master keys right now, right?
Tears, shots, speed...
That's not good enough.
D10, devolves all enemies in the room into another.
Enemies of lower difficulty.
Nah, I think we're gonna re-roll this.
Oi!
Well, hello.
That's fine.
I had too much anyway.
That's good, I had too little.
Beautiful.
Absolutely lovely.
Now I'm gonna buy a heart, I think.
Tears, yeah, re-roll.
Okay, what do we got?
Black candle?
Black heart, immunity to floor curses, immunity to negative effects from certain items.
Increases chance of encountering dev...
Yes.
Very good.
I don't even want to look at the others.
Okay, this blue heart is good, but I'm gonna take this...
That was pretty good!
Space is made up with bombs!
Oi, yoi, yoi.
Nice!
Gimme those coins.
So much farting.
We gotta get a key now, though.
It's for sale!
Wait, here's the normal one!
Notched axe, yeah.
We will do pickaxe press attack, buttons to swing, it can break rocks and damage enemies, but has limited uses for floor.
I'm intrigued.
Now that...
Wait, how does this even work now?
So I'm shooting bombs, but...
So I'm overriding for the third time?
What?
Well, that's totally useless.
Didn't do anything!
Didn't even override it!
That's so sad!
I'm gonna buy this key because it's cheap.
You know what?
I'm gonna get two.
And open some chests.
That's right, I deserve chests.
Black heart!
Yep!
Why do I...
Like, where are these coming from?
There's so many.
Okay, well...
I got three coins now, that means another key for me.
Imagine master key here!
Oh my god, we're rich!
Holy shit!
Let's buy two.
Fuck, that one's already been opened!
I made a mistake.
Eowas?
I think that one's...
Wait, did I just open it by accident?
I didn't mean to.
Shit!
I clicked wrong.
I'm gonna save the last key.
No, I'm not.
No, I'm kidding.
The sun!
But, Eowas.
Let's look for floor decorations.
Honestly, everything looks decorated to me.
Nothing in there.
I don't see anything specific.
Maybe in here?
Yeah, I'm not seeing anything.
Maybe right here, these weird globes on the floor, the glowing ones.
Before we do that, let me activate.
Oh god, they're shooting diamonds?
Oh, they're going achoo!
Oh shit!
This is a mess.
This is a real mess.
I don't know what's happening!
We made it, somehow.
Angel.
Grant me your powers.
Yes!
That's amazing.
Love it.
That was incredible.
Eowas.
Let me dig right here.
Come on, Eowas.
Yeah!
So that does count.
Fantastic.
All right, little guys, this is for you!
Yeah, I couldn't avoid that.
Wait, what is the point of this place?
There's nothing in here.
I don't know.
That's weird.
Well, well, well.
I have one coin.
No keys.
Dang.
Moving on, I guess.
Oh!
Wait.
Glitch it.
Maybe we can now somehow get in?
Game is glitched.
Worth experimenting with.
Okay, now we go here.
I hate that one.
Decreases Isaac's size.
Spawns a random...
That's not super good, either.
Oh, wait a minute!
This is a familiar, right?
Blocks, shots, and deals contact damage.
I don't think I'm gonna be able to shoot from it, though.
But this one is very underwhelming.
I'll take this.
Yeah, it's not shooting.
Nothing.
We got the devil music here.
Whoa, this one is five...
Oh, dude, that's actually huge for me.
What was that?
Oh, thanks.
I'm gonna blow up some stuff.
Shit!
Okay, they're dead.
Blow it all up!
What the fuck!
Why are you shooting me?
Dumbass!
Oh, no!
What?
That triggers it!
Oh, that's cool.
I didn't know that.
That's amazing.
Luckyfoot.
Increase the chance of getting room clear rewards.
Turns out winning rewards from...
converts bad pill effects into good pill effects.
I mean...
Didn't I also get this bomb last time I was playing Greed?
Like, I get it every time I play Greed.
All right, let's go.
It's time for the...
Oh, right.
I take damage from spikes.
That's a thing.
What's happening?
Uh-oh.
I'm just bombing randomly hoping something sticks.
This is the plan right now.
Holy!
All right.
You like...
You like big bada-boom?
I can big bada-boom.
Big bada-boom.
Muji pass.
You are dead.
Oi!
Careful now.
Careful!
I keep spawning these chests.
What are these enemies?
I'm scared.
Wait, there's a trap door over there.
Dude, will you die?
I don't understand why these chests are spawning.
I don't get it.
Why is this happening?
What the fuck is going on?
Man!
Contagion.
Uh, right.
Sure.
I gotta go heal.
Oh man, I need keys.
I need healing.
Um, if I take one of these, something else will spawn though, right?
So this one's only three.
That means I can buy that and this one.
Do I really want it though?
Or do I just go full key?
Oh man, the plus five keys are gone.
So sad, I'm gonna buy these.
Two of those.
Open this guy.
Yeah!
Absolutely yes!
Increase the chance of encountering...
Yep, why not?
Heal me, baby!
Oh yeah!
Now we're cooking with diesel.
Another key for me.
Oh, that's beautiful.
Oh, that's...
That is amazing looking.
I'm not gonna pick it up yet though.
Because we still have things to do.
Here's the plan.
I'm gonna go in a corner and just bomb the shit out of myself.
Come at me, bro!
Come on!
Fucking dare you, double dare you, motherfucker!
I dare you to come next to me, brother!
God, it feels amazing!
All right.
Give me the fucking money!
Give me the money, Lebowski!
Another key for me.
No!
What a troll.
I need more keys.
Okay, fine.
You know what?
Go in here.
Infinite healing!
Who cares?
Love puberty.
Love lockdown.
Come on, Den.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Dude, we're gonna find secrets!
Oh my god.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah!
Money!
Okay.
I'm gonna get...
I'm gonna save my money, actually.
Save my money a little bit.
Now we go down here and look for more secrets.
Boink!
Right over there.
Right over here.
And here, perhaps.
Okay, nothing.
Man, I wish I could blow up these chests.
That would be amazing.
Come at me, bro!
Come at me!
I dare you!
Where did you go?
That's cool.
You can do that.
That's awesome.
Goodnight.
Dude, imagine we could step with this!
Imagine stepping right now!
The step would go hard.
That would be the ultimate step.
Holy shit.
Come at me!
Oh, yeah.
Oh, this is...
This is so euphoria-inducing!
I am on cloud nine.
I love it!
Heal me.
All right, now what?
Now what?
What do I do?
Go in here?
I can't buy anything, though.
Get a step on that.
Uh, wait a sec.
Do I want to do that?
Oh!
What?
I didn't go in there!
I didn't move my character!
There's gravity!
My what?
Strength.
Okay, nice.
I think I'm okay here.
We're moving on.
Imagine getting the mama mega now, as well.
That would be great.
I may actually get keys.
More keys for me.
Then we're gonna go open some treasure chests here.
Money!
Consolation prize!
What is it?
It's a shot speed.
No, shot...
It's tears.
Mom's ring!
Random rune or so...
Yeah.
What is it?
Rune shard?
Grand's a weaker effect of a...
Okay.
Wait a minute, strength?
Plus one health.
Okay.
Now we go buy more keys, I think.
Or I save it!
I save the money?
No.
Keep gambling.
Keep gambling!
Keep a track of what I've opened, though.
This one I have not.
Rainbow worm.
Tear cycle through different worm effects.
Are there worm effects on this?
I don't think that works.
Yeah, crack jacks!
Crack my jack, brother.
Chance to heal half a red heart each time you clear a room?
That doesn't matter to me.
Come on now.
Who do you think I am?
Crap this!
We're leaving.
See ya, nerds!
Oh, shit.
Go!
There's a huge chest on the little icon now.
Money me?
Oh, we're in the shop room, I guess.
This is the shop place.
Faded Polaroid.
Isaac gains camouflage.
Enemies are also confused while camouflaged.
That can be used.
Okay, whatever.
Wait, what?
Can be used to open a strange door!
Hold on.
Faded.
Hole.
Open strange door.
This one is good as well.
Actually, any increase in tears right now would be a massive boon to me.
What I gotta say for it.
Find secrets.
Nothing there?
I don't believe that.
Money!
That is huge.
Yeah!
Look at this money!
Holy!
We're gonna keep finding secrets now.
Nothing.
Don't buy that accidentally.
Pay to win?
Pay to play.
Plus five coins.
I mean, why wouldn't I take this?
That's incredible!
Imagine the chests!
Dude, that's actually crazy!
I'm gonna buy this as well.
I think.
Wait, I could also re-rule.
That was the effects of most cards.
I'm gonna buy this.
No, I will wait a bit.
Let's start whatever this is.
All right, come at me then.
This is incredible!
Dude, we're gonna open all these chests!
What is happening, brother?
Yeah, bomb me.
That's good.
I like bombs.
Come on, keep bombing.
Buy those only chests anyway, whether they come from.
I don't understand.
There's too many fucking chests.
I don't even know what's happening.
I don't even understand what's happening.
I'm taking all of the upgrades.
I don't even know what I'm taking, but I'm taking them, you know?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, just keep taking.
We like taking.
Oh, backpack, I'll take that.
I'll take...
Dude, I barely can...
I can't move.
Oh, that's the flying baby kid.
Holy shit, get me the fuck out of there, okay.
Buy this.
We're gonna buy this.
I need more money.
I understand why this mode is called greed mode.
It all makes sense.
What is that blue one?
Something blue there.
Ramming speed.
The stars are calling.
Damn right they are.
Purple heart.
Well, oh, I clicked the button.
I didn't mean to.
He's greedy.
Yo, listen.
You became Lord of the Flies.
An angry fly has appeared.
Oh my god.
The thing...
I don't even know what I want.
Like, tech zero has appeared.
I don't understand what's happening.
Okay, let me actually have a look here.
What do I want?
It's hard to navigate, you know?
A new pill is...
Dude, I'm unlocking an insane amount of stuff right now.
Let me take a look at my items.
Yeah, I have a lot of items.
That's a lot of items right there.
Oh, we're going again.
There's a boss somewhere.
Where's the boss?
Spot the boss.
Maybe there's a converter somewhere.
I need a converter.
Bro, what is that even?
I don't even know what's happening.
Oh, wait.
I don't have bombs anymore.
I have something else.
I have something...
I have VR goggles on or something.
I don't know what's happening.
There's too much!
Is that a wafer?
That's a wafer.
Wafers are good.
Dude, I'm losing more money than I'm getting somehow.
I need money.
There's a PhD right there.
Easiest PhD of my life.
What is that one?
Technology 2, extra laser.
I mean, sure.
At some point, we're going to be done here, right?
No, we have the Bible, too.
Joker teleports to the devil or angel.
Yo, let's try that.
No way.
Rosary, three soul hearts?
Adds copies of the Bible to all item pools.
Wait, I need to choose, right?
That's a new one.
Flight plus H?
Yo, flight is going to be huge here.
Hell yeah.
Oh, much easier to navigate.
Oh, nice.
I can actually walk through this level now.
That's insane.
Okay, bombs are key.
I have golden bombs or something.
I don't know what's happening there.
Continuum.
I mean, honestly, at this point, guys, we're just going to go.
Because I don't know what's even happening right now.
I can't deal with that.
It's too much for me.
I can't deal with it.
We're just going to look at all my fucking followers.
I don't know what's happening.
We're just...
Oh, wait, we can't go yet or...
How do we actually go?
Wait a minute.
What do we do here?
What's the point?
How am I at zero coins?
There must be some effect that I have that absorbs coins.
Wait, how do I get out of here?
Oh, there we go.
That's amazing.
Ultra greed.
Well, this is going to be fun.
What do I even have?
So, what?
What just happened?
Puberty.
Wait, am I just getting items?
What?
Why?
I'm an adult now.
I'm not even going to try to understand how any of this works right now.
I'm just...
You know what?
What's that one?
Range?
We can use a little bit more range, I guess.
Louse, is she tasty?
Just go.
Honestly.
I don't even like...
The problem is, I don't have bombs anymore, so...
But I can make bombs.
I can still put bombs down.
So, that's how I'm going to heal.
What is that?
Monkey paw?
Spawns a black heart when Isaac is reduced to half a heart.
Wish me luck.
Wait, what?
Oh.
I'm going to stand on top of him and go crazy with the bomb.
I don't know where my character is.
I don't...
I don't care.
I don't know what's happening!
Ha ha ha!
Lemon squeeze!
Party!
Oh, you're dead, son!
You're dead, son!
Box of friends!
Uh, well, I would love to donate!
I don't have any money!
How is this real?
Uh...
Can I bomb this?
Dude, my bombs are crazy.
Look at this.
That is an insane bomb!
Oh, wait, I can charge something up.
Look!
Jeez!
Wait, what did I do?
I didn't click anything!
What's happening?
Creepy.
Well, that was a run.
What do you say to that?
I un...
Like, next time, I will spend...
half an hour just going through everything I've unlocked.
Because that was insane.
I need to look at all the shit that happens.
Wow.
Damn.
Now you know what's possible?
Dude, I don't even know what happened.
It was too much for my brain.
I can barely understand a normal run.
That stuff?
Wow.
Don't even know what's happening, dude.
Like, what was that?
Yeah, I figured that was a way to break the game, Alexis.
I got a taste of it a little bit.
When you can spawn hearts and then when you take damage, you can...
spawn hearts from the damage you take and then use those hearts on the donation machine to get more items and back and forth, you know?
There were different ways to do it, I guess.
But yeah, that run was one for the books, for sure.
Like, it doesn't get any more crazy than that, I don't think.
Maybe it does.
But that, like, it's like everything aligned that run, you know?
Yeah, I know, Slow Fluenza.
I should have taken it slow, but how ca- I was too excited!
Like, so much stuff was happening, I was just going along with it.
It's like me being, I don't know, at a disco or something and the best track comes on, you know?
And you're at the right...
just the perfect amount of drunk and you can't stop dancing, you know?
That's what I was in, in that moment.
I was in a flow state.
Is Data Miner high on your list of favorite items?
I don't even know what Data Miner is.
I guess I got an item named Data Miner?
I got a million items just now.
Oh, that was the Pig Axe!
Oh, okay, I see.
I thought it was just called Pig Axe or something.
Oh, it makes sense with the Miner.
Data Miner.
Ah, right, I see it.
Makes sense.
Guys, wasn't this run like even before everything started breaking?
Wasn't this just the weirdest run ever?
It started off horribly.
I got a terrible item that made me not able to summon my second familiar.
And then it just got worse and worse and then it went up and then it went down and then it just went crazy.
It's pretty much like a stock market graph.
That's what happened here.
A very volatile stock.
That got pumped and dumped.
And then pumped.
And then it stayed like that.
It's safe to say nobody ever had such a run before in the whole of humanity.
Is that true, though?
I guess there are many possibilities.
So the chance of someone getting my exact items is like pretty much impossible, right?
Data Miner creates glitched items.
Yeah, I noticed.
It was really like...
Okay, maybe you guys can tell me.
I will ask you this.
Rotund.
The item I got that was called Stairwell.
Stairway, yeah, Stairway.
That had something to do with it, right?
Everything that happened.
That's what I think.
Yes, okay, okay, yeah.
I figured that item was somehow breaking everything for me.
Glitched item, got it.
But dude, when I found the pyromaniac, I knew already at that point, okay, this run is won, no matter what happens.
Like, it can't go wrong now.
That was just like, okay, this run is done.
No matter what happens, I'm gonna win.
Because I knew I could just stand in a corner and bomb myself, right?
For once, must be a bug was true.
Hell yeah.
Guys, I was right for once.
It actually was a bug.
Remember coffee?
Oh, that's right.
I totally forgot about coffee.
Holy shit.
I got too absorbed again because I kept losing with Lazarus.
So I kept playing.
I should have made a coffee, actually.
Then again, did I really need a coffee?
Did I really need more energy towards the end?
I don't think I did.
It may have been too much, even for me to handle.
Dopamine maxing, yes.
I actually had a brief moment of uh-oh.
I may have fucked this up at the very end.
When I realized that I wasn't shooting bombs anymore.
You know, and I couldn't heal myself.
But then I was like, oh wait, I have a hundred bombs.
I can just place.
I was like, oh, okay, we're good.
Early this stream, you were like, where are my bombs?
When you had an active item that created...
Oh, yeah, I don't deny that.
That probably happened.
Oh, I had a large...
Yeah, I was wondering because at the very end, I charged up.
I made a massive explosion and I think I destroyed something and then the game just ended.
I'm not sure what exactly happened there.
Maybe I actually just walked into the chest without realizing.
Yeah, okay, I figured it was something like that.
Like briefly, I thought, wait, did I just blow open the door and discover some kind of crazy ending or something, you know?
Do you want me to knock back?
Yeah.
Absolute insanity.
Yeah, zero coins in the machine idea.
Like, what the hell?
I think...
Don't tell me, of course, but I'm pretty sure I picked up some kind of item or familiar that basically ate all my coins.
Or I got some kind of upgrade that made it so that when I picked up coins, it got converted to something else, you know?
So I guess a little unlucky on that front, but...
Yeah, don't tell me.
I'll probably encounter it again in the future.
You can say Clueless all you want, that's fine.
I mean, I am Clueless regarding a lot of this.
I'm still a new player, you know?
Even though I have quite a bit of hours in this game now, I still feel like I don't know anything.
Like, I am so new.
I'm so green, you know?
Newbie.
Will you have bot review?
No, actually.
Because I'm pretty...
I did figure out the losing heart thing.
That was one thing I wanted to check in the bot, actually, but now I know.
Game break always feels like fever dream.
Well, that game break was insane, right?
Like, the amount of chests in that room was...
I actually got a little scared that I may crash the game.
Or that all the chests would softlock me so that I couldn't pass through anymore.
But I was already so deep into it, I couldn't stop, you know?
Like, that was wild.
Dude, when I found the item that made me be able to open chests with coins, I knew this was gonna go wild.
I already had a feeling like, okay, what does this mean?
Does it even work on the chests?
I was so curious about that.
It was close to crash, you think?
Oh, shit, okay.
I'm glad it didn't crash.
Even though a crash would have been cinematic in its own way.
I wouldn't have minded that.
That would have been a cool way to end it.
If you're ever scared of crashing the game, you can always save by exiting and continuing.
Okay, that's a good tip, thanks.
I'm actually gonna remember that.
The Jira at the end, imagine duplicating everything?
No, wow.
Wow.
You understand now where your coins went?
Oh, yeah, of course.
Right.
I opened too many chests.
All right.
Guys, that was a freaking banger.
This may have been my favorite stream so far of this game.
Because that just went wild.
That went completely off the rails at the end.
In the best way possible.
What an experience.
Now I'm like, I'm never gonna discount a run ever again.
Because that run started off so bad and it ended up so weird and cool.
So no matter what happens in the future, I'm always gonna go with this thought of, okay, anything can happen, you know?
It doesn't matter what the current situation is.
Things can go crazy.
Yeah.
All runs are winnable.
Well, of course.
I mean, if you have perfect dodge and you're amazing at just, you know, avoiding everything, then yeah, obviously.
Technically, you're right.
Of course, I'm just not that good, you know?
That's the problem.
All right, guys, I'm out of here.
Thanks for watching.
I'll see you next time.
Good night.